<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Han Ngo]]></title>
  <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/"/>
  <updated>2020-06-02T02:20:45+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Han Ngo]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[nntruonghan@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The NeXT Bytes: Prologue]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/the-next-bytes/"/>
    <updated>2020-06-02T01:11:46+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/the-next-bytes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>The Standing-ground</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;m a software engineer, innovation advocates and technology investor. I created <a href="golang.org.vn">Golang Vietnam</a> Community and helped run <a href="webuild.community">WeBuild Community</a>. On those platforms, we connect with all the makers and software engineers from different background and support them on their side projects.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m the founder of <a href="dwarves.foundation">Dwarves Foundation</a> (<a href="https://github.com/dwarvesf">@dwarvesf</a>), a technology firm that focuses on tech know-how R&amp;D and massive application/distribution via a wide range of activities and services, e.g. offshore centre, software consulting, open-source software development. At Dwarves Foundation, we choose innovation to be one of our core values that form ideas to affect the general society undoubtedly. Innovation is not for geniuses working alone; it is an activity that requires a team effort. Being innovative is a part to approach the new era.</p>

<p>I also founded <a href="dwarves.ventures">Dwarves Ventures</a>, the investment arms of Dwarves Foundation. We invested in a few startups that want to build next favorite things. One of our investment is <a href="superbits.co">Super Bits</a>. It&rsquo;s a product team that dedicated to making software &amp; tools for programmers and development team.</p>

<h2>We are heading to the future</h2>

<p>Throughout the years, we still believe that the best way to predict the future is to invent it. In the run to the future, we are continually working and exploring new technologies, frameworks and methodologies. While we actively involve in software development, we also have the opportunity to work with many startups, founders, business owners and software team, which make us one of the best witness to pragmatic innovation transformation.</p>

<p>The interest and area of knowledge keep expanding around technological know-how and practices to build sustainable businesses, in variety of</p>

<ul>
<li>Teamwork &amp; Leadership</li>
<li>Business and Organization Structure</li>
<li>Product Development</li>
<li>Software Design</li>
<li>Digital Transformation &amp; Automation</li>
<li>Data-driven &amp; Business Intelligent</li>
</ul>


<p>And also</p>

<ul>
<li>Working with Startups</li>
<li>Investment &amp; VC Point of View</li>
<li>Business Model Analysis</li>
<li>Innovation and Methodology</li>
<li>Everything else Science x Technology related</li>
</ul>


<p>And <strong>The NeXT Bytes</strong> is a monthly memo where we want to share these experiences, observation and research summary. Together with my crew, we intend to provide a sense of the goings-on in the tech industry, with more than thousands subscribers who are founders, makers, software engineers, designers, product guys and technologist. As we are going to explore the future, we don&rsquo;t know what it holds, but the journey will be exciting.</p>

<p>The name <a href="https://tinyletter.com/nextbytes/"><strong>The NeXT Bytes</strong></a> is inspired by Apple NeXTSTEP OS and also through the fact that Technology &amp; Software continues to drive the world. Everything is running on code which consists of trillion of billion of <em><strong>zero &amp; one</strong></em> bits combined. We want to look at the bright side of the future where the next generation of Bytes would be elegant, well-written and would make the world a better place.</p>

<p>Subscribing to this newsletter is a way keep up with these updates, with a message sent directly to your inbox.</p>

<blockquote><p>Subscribe: <strong><a href="https://tinyletter.com/nextbytes/">https://tinyletter.com/nextbytes/</a></strong></p></blockquote>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2020-06-02-next-bytes.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2020 Resolutions]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/2020/"/>
    <updated>2020-03-01T02:42:05+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/2020</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The last 10 years was quite a ride. Turning from a kid to a man, I have grown more than my expected thanks to a long list of mentors, brothers, and sisters. It is 2020, and I&rsquo;d like to make it special to kick start the next 10 years. Here come the resolutions for this year.</p>

<h4>Dwarves Foundation</h4>

<p>The company we founded in 2015 has turned 5 and reached its first milestone. It&rsquo;s about time to step down and let others take the throne.</p>

<ul>
<li>Transition: Some transitions are needed for the next generation to take over the company. Everything is quite in shape. The business model is firm. We have a great team of 50-ish, a growth rate of 60% since Day 1, a worth-to-pursue vision, a few missions ahead to accomplish, a playbook with all of our best practices, and a few good hires last year. I&rsquo;m looking for a new CEO for Dwarves Foundation.</li>
<li>Territory: With a good record serving customers in the last 5 years and everything are in place; the business expansion expects to happen both online and offline. Most of the time, we meet and work with our clients via the internet. The pattern works so far, but I believe there&rsquo;s still room for improvement. Why not try to take another business approach? I&rsquo;m looking for business partners to explore the market that we haven&rsquo;t touched.</li>
<li>Employee-owned company: Last year, we distributed company shares to the early employees and had the first batch of dividend pulled off. This year, we will continue to issue the ESOP to the rest privately. Every member who stays with the company for more than 2 years will have chances to earn company stakes.</li>
<li>Fully automation &amp; Data-driven operations: The best part of running your tech company? You have a vast workforce to try all the cool kinds of stuff. We have the data of every part of daily operations, from project development to personal development. All the hiring, branding campaigns, or even accounting &amp; payroll adjustments should base on data. It will help reveal the hidden aspect that you&rsquo;ve ever notice.</li>
<li>A getaway office: It&rsquo;s my dream to have an unconventional office space where the dwarves can escape the city and hang around. One in the mountain and one near the beach. Still, a long way to go.</li>
</ul>


<h4>Dwarves Ventures</h4>

<p>Taking the build capability to the step further, Dwarves Ventures is a micro VC that makes use of our knowledge, experience for years to help tech startups with business &amp; financial models, pitch assist, product design, market testing, MVP &amp; platform development. All the materials, metrics, and tractions to achieve before getting to series A funding round.</p>

<p>Last year, we made an investment into 2 local tech startups in Vietnam in exchange for 5 to 20 percent in equity. One major in Hospitality and one in Wholesale Marketplace. This year, among with the expansion of our core business and Craftsmanship Study Program, we hope to meet more exceptional founders.</p>

<h4>Superbits</h4>

<p>The internet used to be a fun place. Growing up, I couldn&rsquo;t find the same excitement. As per the prediction for the next decade, people tend to lean over the different &amp; personalized, I decided to found the Superbits to help bring those excitement bits back. And we are not the only team want to do that, there&rsquo;s another that bring cool bits back to the internet for years. One of them: <a href="https://100r.co">100r.co</a></p>

<p>We started last year with a few macOS apps to help with the productivity boost. This year we will continue to look at this same topic.</p>

<h4>A hedge fund for indie &amp; retail investors</h4>

<p>We build an autobot &amp; apply quantitative methods into the global financial trading market, dedicated to producing exceptional returns. For the exceptional returns, I mean a few bucks for hundreds USD saving, LOL. It can&rsquo;t make us rich but can help make life easier, financially. It is still in beta testing, and I&rsquo;m looking for friends who are interested in &amp; also want to get the first taste. Please drop me a message at <a href="&#109;&#x61;&#x69;&#108;&#x74;&#x6f;&#58;&#x68;&#x61;&#x6e;&#x40;&#x63;&#x61;&#x73;&#x68;&#x62;&#97;&#x67;&#x2e;&#120;&#121;&#122;">&#x68;&#97;&#x6e;&#x40;&#x63;&#x61;&#115;&#x68;&#x62;&#x61;&#103;&#46;&#x78;&#x79;&#x7a;</a></p>

<h4>Learn another language</h4>

<p>I barely speak English. It&rsquo;s not so proficient, and I&rsquo;m not a type to learn anything to excellence. So instead of getting a higher degree in English, I&rsquo;d love to learn another language. Chinese &amp; Japanese are on my list for now.</p>

<h4>Be a dad</h4>

<p>And finally, be a good dad. Learn to parent. I&rsquo;m going to be a dad in about a month or two. I gave him a cool name, bought him a domain, hodl a few tokens in case they will go skyrocket. I&rsquo;m still not ready for this, but let see what may come in the future.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spring Internship 2019]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/spring-internship-2019/"/>
    <updated>2019-09-08T22:08:12+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/spring-internship-2019</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>The program</h3>

<p>This is a second Internship Program at Dwarves Foundation. Held in Spring of 2019, we handpicked every single candidate that passed our CCAT test. Changing our measurement metrics from the last program, we aim to select the candidates not just with strong background, bilingual, and also we feel that they are unconventional.</p>

<p>Over 160 candidates, we only selected 12. They are divided into three groups, each group with people from backend, mobile, and web.
Golang is still the primary language that they have to learn and practice in the first month. Golang is a handy but straightforward language to get people on the same coding page. With Golang they can quickly pick up the language and then focus on the problem set they need to solve.</p>

<p>After the first month, they went back to their career choice. If they want to do web, at this point in time, they will know a whole web front and the backend. If they want to do mobile development, they will know how the backend works, not just their view components. For the backend guy, we will continue to teach them a bit of how the deployment works. The main point is still to get them the whole picture of the system they gonna build.</p>

<p>Learning from the last program, this year, we tried to add in the missing pieces of software development knowledge that they haven&rsquo;t been taught in school or in open source projects. To distinguish Coder, Programmer, and Software Engineer, they need to learn the difference. The training program includes a quick glance over</p>

<ul>
<li>Software Engineering Introduction</li>
<li>Software Modelling</li>
<li>Software Architecture</li>
<li>Software Construction</li>
<li>Software Process</li>
<li>Software Quality</li>
</ul>


<script async="true" class="speakerdeck-embed" data-ratio="1.77777777777778" data-id="82a845337784492580099fc2fe264db5" src="https://speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js"> </script>


<h3>Its goal</h3>

<p>The program was designed to bring hands-on experience to the candidates. Applying Pair Programming practice, we assign each group to a specific mentor. They had their time learned from the mentors on the developing products.</p>

<ul>
<li>A DevOps web app wrapping over Google Cloud, Azure, and AWS to provide a single interface, manage an entire lifecycle of an application.</li>
<li>A system that aggregates schedule from all the sports events and deeply integrates to your personal calendar.</li>
</ul>


<p>Experience all the best practices from codebase structure; multiple environments from development, testing, staging, and production; gitflow with pull request and code review, microservices architecture, etc.
All the cutting edge technologies from k8s, AWS deployment, react redux, Netlify, Cloudflare &hellip;</p>

<h3>Highlights</h3>

<h4>The metrics</h4>

<ul>
<li>Strong background</li>
<li>Bilingual</li>
<li>Unconventional</li>
<li>Growth potential</li>
</ul>


<p>We say yes to students with a strong foundation, growth potential, and good English. The student with a strong foundation has a step forward compared to other students. They can pick up thing very quick and ready for the real project. The candidates with a right attitude toward professional will win the position.</p>

<h4>Average age</h4>

<p>The best year to apply for an internship at Dwarves Foundation?
We think the senior students are the most suitable for the internship program. We are likely picking 80% of senior students than 3rd year and 2nd year. The senior students will have more chance to focus on fulltime job after their graduation.</p>

<h4>Diversity</h4>

<p>There are more female candidates this year. We love to increase gender diversity in the team to bring perspectives. Despite the fact that female staff still have disadvantages to win the leadership position due to stress and heavy workload.</p>

<h4>Culture</h4>

<p>The interns love our culture. Having a healthy team culture provides a good environment for self-developing. It feels like they are already a part of the team.</p>

<h4>Time</h4>

<p>Three months are still too short for them to absorb the program. The first month is for fundamental catching up. The next two months are for hands-on experience.</p>

<h4>Next program</h4>

<p>Despite the fact that all the metrics are essential, we feel that during the first days of their careers, the attitude is the most important characteristic. The next batch should be more on attitude over skill. 80% of interns with good attitude tend to be hardworking</p>

<h4>University</h4>

<p>Candidates from top universities like the University of Science or the University of Technology have a stronger background than others. But at the same time, they are not bilingual, which affect their confidence in working in multiple culture environment. Top candidates learned English by themselves.</p>

<h4>Technology</h4>

<p>80% of candidates want to learn technologies over foundation knowledge. Most of them can&rsquo;t tell the difference between software service firm and product company. Trendy technologies like blockchain and AI still catch their eyes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DFG: Dwarves Foundation Gem]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/dfg-dwarves-foundation-gem/"/>
    <updated>2019-08-27T01:01:41+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/dfg-dwarves-foundation-gem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4>Foundation token: DFG</h4>

<p>Following the practice of Securities Token Offering, we are getting our tokens considered as shares with <a href="https://github.com/ethereum/EIPs/blob/master/EIPS/eip-884.md">ERC-884</a>. The tokens &amp; its transactions are recording in Ethereum decentralized computing network, powered by blockchain technology. In other terms, owning one token simply equals owning one share of the company, which entitles the shareholder of all his rights, notably voting and dividend rights.</p>

<p>The token value reflected by the valuation of the company by evaluating</p>

<ul>
<li>Assets (furniture, computers, cash, AR, investments, etc)</li>
<li>Liabilities (debt, AP, current payroll, leases, etc)</li>
<li>Present value of expected future profits (growth rate)</li>
</ul>


<p>The token was naming:  DFG / Dwarves Foundation Gem. The first contract was deployed to Ethereum network last week, and you can track it on <a href="https://etherscan.io/token/0x36779A12eAb9B054bc991143751Ed5B05568eE8d">Etherscan</a>.</p>

<p>This also marks our first milestone in building our global software firm. We have a plan for all of us to be financially happy in the long-term goal where the dwarves could own parts of the company.</p>

<h4>The first allocation</h4>

<p>The first batch of tokens (RSU) will be issued to those very first members of Dwarves Foundation who has dedicated themselves to the development of the company from Day 1.</p>

<p>Beside the joined date and contribution, the allocation also reflects the risks that you decided to take with the team. High risk high pay.</p>

<ul>
<li>Quang Le: joined on Feb 2015, Quang is the 3rd member. During his soon-to-be five years serving the company vision, he has dedicated himself into everything, from day-to-day activities, project works, and the true craftsmen behind the company infrastructure. Thanks for all the hard works.</li>
<li>Hieu Phan: joined on May 2015, the 5th member. Without his help and dynamics from Day 1, the team couldn&rsquo;t make it till today. Thanks for all the hard works.</li>
<li>Huy Giang: joined on Sep 2016. Taking the position of Frontend Lead, his specialty, work ethic, and contributions help to increase the engineering standard. Thanks for all the hard works.</li>
<li>Minh Tran: joined on April 2017 as Operations, PM and Frontend Dev. Although it was quite a challenge for Minh at the moment, his efforts to get things done was recognized and highly appreciated. Thanks for all the hard works.</li>
</ul>


<h4>What to expect after the first batch?</h4>

<ul>
<li>There&rsquo;s still a large amount of tokens reserved for people who can bring us to the next level as we are still missing a few important positions: VP of Engineering, VP of Business Development and Technical PM.</li>
<li>On this October, the valuation dashboard will go live at <a href="https://ir.d.foundation">https://ir.d.foundation</a></li>
<li>The Foundation directors who are committing to the company will receive the Options Plan with huge discount. Performance review required.</li>
<li>End of this December, a few more tokens will be reserved for key members which they could buy via ESOP. Also a few rewards for 2019 contributions.</li>
<li>Publish ESOP policy for all members. 20% discount.</li>
<li>And finally, for members from last internship programs, you will be given the challenges when you reach the middle level.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Unconventional]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/the-unconventional/"/>
    <updated>2019-07-17T00:11:35+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/the-unconventional</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You might have known that I&rsquo;m building the software organization called The Dwarves in the last four years. The team reached the size of 50 several months ago. The average member age is around 26. They are smart and talented. They are young, well-educated, and hard-working toward success.</p>

<p>With a different expectation in engineering standard, we rarely hire people outside of our circle. We handpick and recruit the individual whom we feel they are the one matching with the engineering-driven culture that we are pursuing. We also decided to hire high potential freshers and train them from scratch. It&rsquo;s costly to do such a thing, but we believe good things take time. That&rsquo;s the way we hire for culture (and values).</p>

<p>The culture we are pursuing is the combination between the unconventional spirit and the will to do the right things in every piece of our decision, not just follow the existing of which has been said for years. From the outside perspective, it seems to be ridiculous to develop such an organization:</p>

<ul>
<li>from gather people with like mind and build the organization we&rsquo;d love to work at</li>
<li>where judgments are fair and run by the right ideas</li>
<li>people payout are equal to their contribution so they can make money and be cool at the same time</li>
<li>people should commit to the quality, not the sales quantity</li>
<li>the team members have time to think about the next problem they want to solve or can join the team on self-development progress.</li>
</ul>


<p>It&rsquo;s like Utopia for software engineers and innovators.</p>

<p>The thought about an unusual business approach, high risk, and considerable chances to fail often appear in my head. But things are getting confident in me over time. There are few companies out there did the same thing, and they stood out.</p>

<p>Remember when Steve Job talked about why he didn&rsquo;t hire the professional managers? In the fast-paced industry like tech, the developer turned manager rule the works. The professional managers can&rsquo;t do crap about that. Managing at Dwarves Foundation is a part-time occupation, next to being involved with doing the work itself.</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rQKis2Cfpeo" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>


<p><strong>And running by ideas is the best way to hire great people.</strong></p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/f60dheI4ARg" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>


<p><strong>Some companies care about the work output, not chairs.</strong></p>

<p><a href="https://basecamp.com/books/remote"><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2019-07-16-guessing.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Or when they accept the truth that planning is guessing.</strong></p>

<p><a href="https://basecamp.com/books/rework"><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2019-07-16-planning.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>I love the unconventional way they see and describe the world, not in the fascinating prism but the true nature.</p>

<p>We seek those kinds of people to join our team. The one which is distinctive, with a different approach and can see things in their bare form, know the truth, and be optimistic about the future are the right people we&rsquo;d love to work.</p>

<p>Recently, an intern shared <a href="https://qz.com/1279371/this-physicists-ideas-of-time-will-blow-your-mind/">this post</a> about quantum physics, time and it blew my mind. It reminds me of how lucky I am to have them in the team.</p>

<p>Tech industry is the destination and interference zone between sectors. It&rsquo;s the most fast-pacing environment and the future where human will put all the effort to push its boundary. The Dwarves are running along with the world, and we are welcome you to join us on this journey. We can&rsquo;t promise you the world, but we can guarantee you it will be a fun ride.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Software Engineering Philosophy]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/software-engineering-philosophy/"/>
    <updated>2019-05-23T19:49:02+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/software-engineering-philosophy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2019-05-23-software.png"></p>

<h1>Software is changing the world</h1>

<p>Software is all around us, yet few people think much about the many ways that software impacts the world every day. The history of computing is often said to start with the tactical problems engineers needed to solve in World War II, but it wasn&rsquo;t until 1941 that engineer Konrad Zuse designed a digital computer capable of using software to solve general problems. During the 1950s, standardized programming languages emerged from the need to reproduce old software on new hardware. By the 1960s, software &ndash; until then given away for free with new computers &ndash; was being produced and sold to end users. By the 1980s, software companies saw the potential in the user-friendly graphical interfaces we are now familiar with. Apple started producing operating systems in the mid-1980s and Microsoft in the early 1990s, leading to the era of convenient and fast software. Internet was invented in 1983 with cloud computing and big data era follow up in the next 20 years. Decentralization with p2p communication, blockchain and bitcoin are booming up in the last 5 years. Today, software is all around us.</p>

<p>Software is used by businesses to communicate worldwide. It is used to operate some of the most complex medical machines. It regulates nuclear plants, electrical grids, and other utilities that provide the basics of life. Of course, it is also behind the safe operation of more than 31 million commercial airline flights in the U.S. each year.</p>

<p>Software also helps make life convenient. For example, computer software has made it easier than ever to connect with friends all over the world using social networks. As software becomes more integrated into electronics and appliances, it will continue to simplify life&rsquo;s challenges. As an example, everyone is familiar with how much easier it is to drive from point A to point B thanks to on-board GPS software. Refrigerators can now notify owners about spoiled food; lights around town and in your home can brighten when they detect you walking in the dark; televisions can make suggestions and record your favorite shows based on your preferences.</p>

<p>Whatever the future holds, it is a good bet that software will remain a very important part of it. As computer software becomes more sophisticated, it will help people with more complex challenges. In the future, software may even help us to regulate and improve our own bodies! Today&rsquo;s wearable technology and implanted medical devices are just the beginning of what the next generation of software can do.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s the pass to future. The performance and survival of a large number of organizations now depend on their ability to integrate digital at the heart of their business strategy. The world can&rsquo;t operate without software.</p>

<h1>The Dwarf Principles</h1>

<p>Our definition of Engineering Philosophy, the guiding ideas that help to shape up the way we think and work, to ensure the core values and to deliver quality softwares.</p>

<p>The performance and survival of a large number of organizations now depend on their ability to integrate digital at the heart of their business strategy. This manifesto documents 15 principles that, our team believes, are the cornerstone to creating exceptional digital products that reach their objectives and stand the test of time.</p>

<h2><strong>Engineering Drive</strong></h2>

<p><em>We build a company where software engineering discipline could shine, innovative and quality products are shipped and change the world for the better.</em></p>

<h4>SYSTEMATIC DISCIPLINE</h4>

<p>Software engineering is an engineering discipline that’s applied to the development of software in a systematic approach.</p>

<p>Not applying software engineering methods results in more expensive, less reliable software, and it can be detrimental on the long term, as the changes come in, the costs will dramatically increase.</p>

<h4>ENGINEERS ARE NOT COMMODITIES</h4>

<p>In every software, the engineering team is one of the most imporant factors to make it successful. Software is more of an artisanship, and software engineers aren&rsquo;t a replaceable cog.</p>

<p>People have an assembly line mindset left over from the industrial age. Don’t believe the one-size-fits-all interview process with whiteboarding problems. These serve to grind away the individuality and make us feel like an assembly line worker.</p>

<h4>THE BEST IDEA WINS</h4>

<p>If you have a great idea and the will to see it through, you can effect great change. Nothing is off limits—we’re constantly looking for improvements in our products, our processes, and our people.</p>

<p>All voices are equal here—we hire people to have an opinion and be creative. If your idea makes the most sense, that’s what we’re doing, regardless of your role or seniority.</p>

<p>We learned the practice from an A team, and it is beneficial by helping to strengthen the flat organizational structure.</p>

<p><img class="left half" src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2019-05-23-dwarf.png"></p>

<h2><strong>The Craftsmanship</strong></h2>

<h4>WELL-CRAFTED SOFTWARE</h4>

<p>We humbly demonstrate our expertise by delivering quality software. We work toward perfection in every single piece that we produce. We are proud of the well-crafted software that we develop together. We do not tolerate preventable defects.</p>

<h4>QUALITY PAYS</h4>

<p>Good things take time. Quality must be the top priority. In software work, quality problems overwhelm everything else. When quality isn&rsquo;t managed, entire software projects are unmanageable. Software development is intellectual work. Crafting a high quality software requires not just lots of efforts from a team but also the disciplines and proper methods.</p>

<h4>MIND THE DETAILS</h4>

<p>Details matter. We believe small details equate to big success. As such, creating a product that charms users involves adjusting, refining, and perfecting, over and over again. This attention to detail makes all the difference and creates memorable user experiences.</p>

<h4>CHOOSING THE BORING SOLUTION</h4>

<p>Software development is complex enough by nature. When in doubt, go with the boring solution. Using such a boring solution means that you&rsquo;re using simple vocabulary, which greatly increases the chances of everybody understanding you. This will make it a lot easier for everybody to follow along.</p>

<h4>THINK LONG-TERM</h4>

<p>We do not believe in rushing for project and working overtime. We believe in working sustainably and balanced so that we are a happy bunch of sane workers. Software requires good brains to create good codes and good processes. We do not burn out.</p>

<h4>APPLICATIONS NEED SOLID FOUNDATIONS</h4>

<p>Quality products always rely on a solid foundation. There will be a lot of works running on days, weeks, months, and maybe even years building that application. This constant, never-ending maintenance and extension of an application means that its foundation becomes crucial. Much like with a house, it&rsquo;s not a clever idea to save some money by building just a cheap foundation.</p>

<h4>NOTHING IS PERMANENT</h4>

<p>Software moves fast. New technology has enabled us to create new things. The technology you used yesterday maybe deprecated today. Make sure you understand both the old technology and the new one before buying into the next new thing. New technology needs to provide actual value over existing solutions.</p>

<h2><strong>Minifesto</strong></h2>

<h4>RUNNING LEAN</h4>

<p>Lean philosophy regards everything not adding value to the customer as waste. In order to eliminate waste, one should be able to recognize it. Partially done work, extra processes like paperwork and features not often used by customers are waste. Rework or unnecessarily complex solutions are waste. Waiting for other activities, teams, processes is waste. Managerial overhead not producing real value is waste.</p>

<h4>DELIVER AS FAST AS POSSIBLE</h4>

<p>Make it work. Perfect is an enemy of good. Look for perfection, but not yet. First do it, then do it right, then do it better. Any sufficiently complex system cannot be built out of design, it has to be evolved. The shorter the iterations, the better the learning and communication within the team. The sooner the end product is delivered without major defects, the sooner feedback can be received, and incorporated into the next iteration.</p>

<h4>AIM FOR SIMPLICITY</h4>

<p>Simplicity is complicated. Simple is harder than complex. We have to write code for humans not machines. We want readability. Readable means Reliable. It&rsquo;s easier to understand. It&rsquo;s easier to work on. If it breaks, it&rsquo;s easier to fix.</p>

<h4>EFFECTIVE > PRODUCTIVE</h4>

<p>Being productive is about occupying your time—filling your schedule to the brim and getting as much done as you can. Being effective is about finding more of your time unoccupied and open for other things besides work. We don’t believe in busyness. We believe in effectiveness. Know your priority and do things that matter.</p>

<h4>FAIL FAST, LEARN OFTEN</h4>

<p>Don&rsquo;t be afraid of starting all over again. Evaluate your work constantly. Don&rsquo;t be afraid of throwing to the rubbish a project you&rsquo;ve working on last months. When you start from scratch, innovation comes organically inspired by previous experiences. Evaluate your work constantly.</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2019-05-23-team-images.png"></p>

<h5>WE ARE HIRING</h5>

<p>We are looking for more Dwarves joining us. Have the same DNA and want to build world class products with superb team? Find yourself a seat at: <a href="https://dwarves.careers">https://dwarves.careers</a></p>

<p>We build a dynamic environment where engineers can spend their time working with disruptive startups and be cool at the same time. Checkout engineering life at Dwarves Foundation: <a href="https://dwarves.careers/life/">https://dwarves.careers/life/</a></p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2019-05-23-engineering-life.png"></p>

<blockquote><p>Here&rsquo;s our cat</p></blockquote>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2019-05-23-cat.JPG"></p>

<p>&mdash;</p>

<p>The web version: <a href="https://d.foundation/manifesto">https://d.foundation/manifesto</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2018: Year of Achievement]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/2018-year-of-achievement/"/>
    <updated>2019-01-26T14:41:20+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/2018-year-of-achievement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2019-01-26-homepage.png"></p>

<p>Dwarves Foundation is a software development firm that based in South East Asia. Starting in 2014, we use cutting-edge technology to help tech startups, entrepreneurs and makers to deliver world-class software products.</p>

<h1>The Dwarves of the Year</h1>

<p>Many endeavors have significantly been made by our Dwarves to keep our boat moving over the past year. We have seen the sweat they drop. We have seen the effort they give. We have seen the time we spent together and we cannot stop ourselves treasuring those moments. It gratifies the team to eventually hold an award for the Dwarves of the year.</p>

<p>We understand that success does not come by accident. Breakthrough arrives after hours of working and trying. It pushes us through many considerations to finally reach to these three top-notch nominees among those remarkable hard works:</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2019-01-26-hall-of-fame.png"></p>

<h3>Huy Nguyen — Outstanding</h3>

<p>Considered for his dynamic contribution, Huy distinguishes himself for being enthusiasm towards the work. His striking performance was shown throughout multiple products. Appears to be the frequent workaholic who dedicates his time more than others, Huy did achieve a remarkable growth.
Beside successfully improving the internal competency, Huy is highly recognized for being a dedicated trainer for interns and co-workers.</p>

<h3>Thanh Pham — Honorable Mention</h3>

<p>Thanh differentiates his work performance during the process of development which assigned him the superior skills on visual and animation. Apart from being a devoted employee, he also plays an integral part of backing up the team and training front-end juniors.
Nevertheless, Thanh finds himself hard to fit in with other Dwarves, which explains the reason his ability in leadership is still in need of improvement.</p>

<h3>Hieu Nguyen — Honorable Mention</h3>

<p>Along with achieving breakthrough change on technical skills and meeting deadline on time with high standard workability, Hieu is well known for being proactive and eager to learn new things. Hieu also proves himself as an adept for new Dwarves to look up and get feedback from.
Though he truly give his best for the work, Hieu’s limited ability of teamwork and leadership still prevents him from being more outstanding.</p>

<p>As there is nothing that can help us measure the contribution you have put, we decided to conduct the award by different means. They are expected to claim the prize based on their titles both in cash and in kind, along with a certificate of recognition as a proof of accomplishment, as well as being honored on our Hall of Fame. Every single piece of trying helps us gradually expand the picture. Live long and prosper has been chosen as one of the mindsets to constitute our woodland from the very first day.</p>

<p>For the sake of that to happen, we understand that their benefit comes parallel to the team. So it will be dead wrong if you think there is a benchmark for the means of award. At Dwarves Foundation, recognition does not work that way. The more they contribute, the more guerdon they receive.</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2019-01-26-certificate.jpg"></p>

<h1>2018</h1>

<p>2018 has been a fulfilling year for us with many achievements.</p>

<p>We adapted the new team structure; we redefined things we value.</p>

<p>We doubled the office space. We welcomed new dwarves to join us.</p>

<p>We scaled up from 15 to 40ish with all the smart people gathering around and commit to the dream of building our first global software firm.</p>

<p>We learn new ways to get things done; we live by that for a cutting edge product quality. And we wrap it up with the tedious belief of a better triumph.</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2019-01-26-year-end-party.jpeg"></p>

<p>Everything is just the beginning of our first chapters and it couldn’t be that great without you. I’m very thankful for all the contributions that you have made and looking forward to 2019 with all of you.</p>

<hr />

<h3>We are hiring</h3>

<p>As we are expanding in 2019, we are looking for more Dwarves joining us. Find yourself a seat at: <a href="https://dwarves.careers">https://dwarves.careers</a></p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2019-01-26-tech-stack.png"></p>

<p>Read more at: <a href="http://bit.ly/dwarves-foundation-2018">Medium</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GopherCon Vietnam 2018]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/gophercon-vietnam-2018/"/>
    <updated>2019-01-09T00:19:26+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/gophercon-vietnam-2018</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2018-12-08-homepage.png"></p>

<p>Go (often referred to as Golang) is a free and open source programming language created at Google in 2007 by Robert Griesemer, Rob Pike, and Ken Thompson. The language was announced in November 2009; it is used in some of Google&rsquo;s production systems, as well as by other firms.
Over time, Golang has become the most popular language in large scale IT business where system performance and reliability are the most crucial successful key.</p>

<h1>Golang Vietnam Community</h1>

<p>Back in the day, the Chapter started in the late of 2014 as the playground of Dwarves Foundation, a software development firm based in Saigon. They invested in Go and wanted to help organize the community in Vietnam. In the beginning, there are only a few people in the city that takes Go seriously. They used Go for some of their toy projects. Being one of the first gophers in Vietnam in 2013, Han decided to gather the group of gophers to start the Golang Vietnam Community and put it under the help of Google Developer Group (GDG) Vietnam.</p>

<p>The first meetup was held on 2015 March with more than 50 gophers, and it marked the beginning of the Vietnam chapter. Joining the <a href="https://github.com/golang/go/wiki/GoUserGroups#asia">Go User Groups</a>, Golang Vietnam helps to improve the tech scene by providing lots of activities to gather the community in Vietnam.</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2018-12-08-meetup-01.jpg"></p>

<h1>The GopherCon</h1>

<p>GopherCon is one of the largest Golang events in the world. The first GopherCon was taking place in 2013, held annually in Denver, Colorado by Gopher Academy. Thousand of gophers gather every year to GopherCon to meet and celebrate at the conference together. Followed by the first GopherCon, other communities started their chapter after that.</p>

<p>As a part of the Golang community, we are pleased to be launching the first GopherCon Vietnam, the most significant event in Vietnam dedicated exclusively to Go. A community of a passionate Gophers organizes GopherCon Vietnam on a volunteer basis.</p>

<p>The event was expected to serve 200 &ndash; 250 gophers and last for two days from Dec 08 to Dec 09 with the conference on the first day and the workshop on the second day. The organization rolled out slowly from August with the thought that five months was good enough for us to prepare.</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2018-12-08-sponsors.png"></p>

<p>Since 2014, Golang adoption has been increasing from 3 to more than 50 companies using Go as the primary language in their systems. Therefore, we don&rsquo;t have many struggles finding bits of help and sponsorship from those companies.</p>

<h1>The Conference</h1>

<p>The conference is open for talks from the developer community. Discussions will be for beginners, intermediate and advanced levels, as well as for the interest of everyone. Our scope of topics will include a broad area, anything in the realm of Go language development.</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2018-12-08-stage.jpg"></p>

<p>Speakers submit their talks through PaperCall: <a href="https://www.papercall.io/events/1359">https://www.papercall.io/events/1359</a> and we will pick the best topics from that. List of talks as follows</p>

<ol>
<li>Opening &ndash; 9 Years of Go</li>
<li>Starting Serverless with Go</li>
<li>Go on a journey away from the mammoth C/C++ monolith</li>
<li>Anatomy of a Docker container</li>
<li>Golang and infrastructure works</li>
<li>How we build scalable architecture at Sendo</li>
<li>An investigative walkthrough of Go channels</li>
<li>Large Scale Data Capture &amp; Experimentation Platform at Grab</li>
<li>Production Ready Microservices at Scale</li>
</ol>


<h1>The Workshop</h1>

<p>Two sessions were conducted by the members from the Golang Vietnam Community, who worked with Go for years will walk you through those topics with hands-on experience. The attendees prepare themselves with laptop and Golang installed on it.</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2018-12-08-workshop-02.png"></p>

<h3>Go Fundamentals</h3>

<p>This class provides an idiomatic introduction to the Go programming language supported by extensive examples and hands-on exercises. Course outline</p>

<ul>
<li>Language Syntax</li>
<li>Using Pointers</li>
<li>Arrays, Slices, and Maps</li>
<li>Methods and Interfaces</li>
<li>Packaging and Exporting</li>
<li>Testing</li>
<li>Managing External Dependencies</li>
<li>Standard Library</li>
</ul>


<h3>Go Intermediates</h3>

<p>This class is for any intermediate-level developer who has some experience with other programming languages and wants to learn Go. Course outline</p>

<ul>
<li>Language Syntax</li>
<li>Data Structures</li>
<li>Interface</li>
<li>Decoupling</li>
<li>Architecture</li>
<li>Concurrency</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2018-12-08-workshop.jpg"></p>

<h1>The Highlights</h1>

<p>The first GopherCon in Vietnam achieved trust and welcoming from the community. We are pleased with that. A quick look at several numbers</p>

<ul>
<li>440 tickets were sold out in 2 weeks including Conference and Workshop.</li>
<li>In 3 months we received more than 50 talks from companies and the Golang community.</li>
<li>More than 65 companies participated in GopherCon Vietnam.</li>
<li>Years of experience distribution of the attendees: Most of the gophers use Golang from 1 to 3 years.</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2018-12-08-year-of-exp.png"></p>

<ul>
<li>Golang was most used for API Development</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2018-12-08-usage-of-golang.png"></p>

<h1>Looking forward</h1>

<p>The GopherCon Vietnam 2018 was a successful event. I want to say thank you to all the people, the volunteers, companies, and organizations that help to make it happened. You guys rock.</p>

<p>For 2019, we would love to hold another one next year and still keep it as volunteer basis with the collaboration from companies that massively adopted Go and from other communities. See you then.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://gophercon.vn">https://gophercon.vn</a></li>
<li><a href="https://golang.org.vn">https://golang.org.vn</a></li>
</ul>


<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/i72-TSxRmpQ" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>


<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2018-12-08-36.jpg"></p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2018-12-08-62.jpg"></p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2018-12-08-63.jpg"></p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2018-12-08-82.jpg"></p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2018-12-08-171.jpg"></p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2018-12-08-242.jpg"></p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2018-12-08-326.jpg"></p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2018-12-08-344.jpg"></p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2018-12-08-352.jpg"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summer Internship 2018]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/summer-internship-2018/"/>
    <updated>2018-11-08T21:52:50+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/summer-internship-2018</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dwarves Foundation is a software development firm that based in South East Asia. We use cutting-edge technology to help tech startups, entrepreneurs and makers to deliver world-class products. We build software and scale cloud platform.</p>

<p>In 2018, we launched the first Summer Internship Program for students with or without Engineering background from top universities in southern Vietnam. The program was designed with the purpose to give an opportunity for candidates to experience the real world projects. No coffee runs here. We love watching talented people learn and explore their skills.</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2018-11-08-banner.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>If you apply for a full-time position, we only want to know if you can bring anything to the table. We get you into the real working environment to see if you can perform well among the team and that’s it. For interns, our approach is different. They are usually quite young and without any experience, so no clues to ask if they can bring in something. The intern candidates will walk through two rounds</p>

<ul>
<li>The first one is the Pre-assessment test in 30 minutes for Computer Software Engineer which is including Criteria Cognitive Aptitude Test (CCAT) and Employee Personality Profile (EPP). CCAT measures your ability to problem solve, use new information, and think critically. It will tell employers how quickly you’ll pick up training for your new role. Research shows that cognitive aptitude is one of the best predictors of your job performance. It’s significantly more predictive than interviews, previous job experience, and your education level. Meanwhile, EPP is a general personality inventory that measures twelve personality traits that provide valuable insights into a person’s work styles and how they are likely to interact with co-workers, management, and customers. It can be used for any position and contains position-specific benchmarks that allow administrators to compare an individual’s scores against composite profiles to determine possible job fit.</li>
<li>The candidates scoring more than 23 points in the first round will go to the second to have an interview with our VP of Engineering. We evaluate the background, the problem-solving mindset and a bit of personality to see if the candidate is the right person.</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2018-11-08-evaluation.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>The program was prepared in 1 month. We posted about the program at the beginning of June and started it from July to October. In such a coincidence, it was also my very first three months working as an Intern when I was 20.</p>

<p>There were 283 applications in total, 142 applicants passed the pre-assessment test and only 14 offers to the interns. That was over our expectation and was the first success for us.</p>

<p>The interns were divided into three small groups: web, mobile, and devops.</p>

<p>We got them to learn Golang as the primary backend language. Golang is Dwarves language of choice to rewrite the modern world. We think as the team the engineers need to understand the core problem that the business wanted to solve, also what is the value that the firm proposes to the customer. Every team members should know the core backend system by getting involved in before building the frontend or dig into the system.</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2018-11-08-golang.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Even though Golang is a quick language to pick up and get things done, the schedule was pretty tight with three weeks learning Go and then one week for a small assignment. All the interns were stretched out to their limit.</p>

<p>After the first month, we arranged them to multiple projects with different challenges:</p>

<ul>
<li>Find Friends is a mobile application with instant location sharing features will allow people to locate friends and family easily.</li>
<li>Smithy is an admin dashboard written in Go and VueJS. It is designed to support multiple existed architectures and databases.</li>
<li>Yggdrasil is a business service mesh written in Go.</li>
</ul>


<p>The internship program was tough but fun. Thank you and congratulation for all the hard work.</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2018-11-08-cert.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Some other fun facts:</p>

<ul>
<li>Most of the interns come from HCM University of Science (US) and University of Information Technology (UIT). They seemed to be more confident and have better engineering background.</li>
<li>Most of them don’t care too much about the company. They want to learn from the people in the company. The internship allowance is not essential.</li>
<li>The average age is 22. The oldest in the batch is 27.</li>
<li>There are three interns studied in a different major, but they decided to join us as Engineer Interns. Brilliant people.</li>
<li>The university in Vietnam teaches them .NET, Java or C++.</li>
<li>And they all think that Blockchain and AI is the most cooling field to work in.</li>
</ul>


<p>More at: <a href="http://dwarves.careers/internship/2018/">http://dwarves.careers/internship/2018/</a></p>

<p>End of the Summer program, we received a few messages from the interns that bring us positive motivation for the next program.</p>

<div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/FWW6hve0GR8" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Dwarves Foundation Stand For]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/what-dwarves-foundation-stand-for/"/>
    <updated>2018-03-19T10:30:20+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/what-dwarves-foundation-stand-for</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Innovation happens. There are many startups found and raise fund every day. They focus on making significant positive changes, impact millions of people, lead to breakthroughs and support the foundation of economic growth.</p>

<p>Building an innovation startup requires lots of different things, and it is tough. Most of them have to deal with business development, legal, fundraising, team recruitment, and product development at the same time. Tech startups need to move fast and break things.</p>

<p>At some points, growing a startup needs a strong and experienced team behind. The software team that can help to design the system, design the database, produce the well-crafted software, keep the system stable, avoid the technical debt and deliver values is one of the critical pieces to solve the puzzle.</p>

<p>Another motivations for Dwarves Foundation was the lack of respect that service firms receive. Most software companies out there focus on digital transformation and consultancy. They do tricks. They hit and run. The codebase they produced is full of crap and it damages our pride.</p>

<p>This is where Dwarves Foundation comes in.
Despite the fact that service firms scale linearly, their ultimate size is capped and small, they don’t have life-changing exits for their founders, we start Dwarves Foundation as we want to build things right. I’ve always felt that companies like Dwarves Foundation are more important to the economy than the mildly pejorative phrase used to describe them.</p>

<p>Dwarves Foundation is an innovation service firm. We have been building an organization with high standard software practices and business growth capabilities, helping tech startups, entrepreneurs and makers deliver their innovative software product since 2013.</p>

<p><strong>We stand for the craftsmanship in software development</strong>. More than telling people how to do things, as a firm, we take responsibility for collaboratively creating the product of innovation with the client. We value the long-term partnership, and we brought the economic impact through massive product distribution and brought to the market by the clients.</p>

<p>We empower innovation with software craftsmanship. This is what we do here. It takes many forms, and we’re always working towards it.</p>

<h3>The Dwarves</h3>

<p>The story begins in Norse Mythology. After the executed of Ymir, the very first giant of the universe, by Odin has conceived a whole new universe. In the new world, Yggdrasill is a giant ash tree located at the center cradles the nine realms of the cosmos.</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2018-03-19-yggdrasill.png"></p>

<p>Dwarf is the small and misshapen creatures that originated as maggots from Ymir’s corpse. They dwell in the mountains deep down in the dark underground of <strong>Svartalfheim</strong>. Dwarves are wisdom, natural good at smithing, mining, and crafting. They are well known for being the best blacksmiths throughout the nine worlds, not only do they have natural abilities to craft weapons and jewelry. They are also excellent engineers and architects.</p>

<p>Dwarvish magic was fundamentally technological know how. They had an unusually high level of skill. There was no shimmering light around the Dwarves, just first rate workmanship. Dwarves greatly pride themselves in their craftsmanship, be it smithing or anything else.</p>

<p>The dwarf is an example of a creature who has the ability that surpasses the known world, presaging the rise of a universe beyond this physical realm. Whatever their origin, the dwarf’s existence plays a role in expanding the imagination.</p>

<p>Aspiring to create a positive breakthrough that can be able to rewrite the new world, we chose the name Dwarves Foundation as the commitment to the vision that we follow.</p>

<p>At our woodland, the Dwarves are encouraged to thoroughly assess and evaluate the product quality before handing it to the customers. By participate in every detail of the work, we take craftsmanship as one of the most fundamental factors of the career transformation for engineers. World-class products require world-class engineers and craftsmanship is what makes it done. Craftsmanship is what flows among the team spirit, or does not exist at all.</p>

<p>We choose innovation to be one of our core values that form ideas to affect the general society undoubtedly. Innovation is not for geniuses working alone, it is an activity that requires the team effort. Being innovative is a part to approach the new era. What that rewards, what can I say, can genuinely lead to significantly remodel the cosmo.</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2018-03-19-dwarves.jpg"></p>

<hr />

<p>Empower innovation is the lifestyle we choose and we are always welcome the like minded people to join us on this journey. A network with all the people who want to change the world would be really awesome. Drop us a message <a href="&#109;&#x61;&#x69;&#x6c;&#116;&#x6f;&#58;&#116;&#x65;&#x61;&#x6d;&#x40;&#100;&#x2e;&#102;&#x6f;&#117;&#110;&#100;&#x61;&#x74;&#105;&#x6f;&#110;">&#116;&#101;&#x61;&#x6d;&#x40;&#100;&#x2e;&#x66;&#x6f;&#117;&#110;&#x64;&#x61;&#116;&#x69;&#111;&#x6e;</a> anytime.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cofounder Agreement]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/cofounder-agreement/"/>
    <updated>2018-02-15T17:41:37+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/cofounder-agreement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Ensure Alignment of Vision</h1>

<p>As you and your cofounder (or cofounders) embark on your entrepreneurial journey together, it’s imperative that you all share the same vision for the purpose and future of your company. It’s easy to get caught up in the thrill of launching a potentially successful startup together, but you all must take the time to establish the existential foundations of the company, and as early as possible, to help prevent the possibility of a drastic falling out later on.</p>

<h3>What Are Your Goals?</h3>

<ul>
<li>Why are you creating this startup?</li>
<li>What need will it fill?</li>
<li>What will your initial product/service offering be?</li>
<li>And what is your strategy for growing the company?</li>
</ul>


<h3>What Are Your Company Values and Philosophy?</h3>

<p>Your company’s success depends on vision alignment (alignment between you and your investors, your employees, and your customers, etc.). Do you share the same priorities? Do you agree on what’s most important to you both personally and for the future of your company?</p>

<h3>How Do You Measure Success?</h3>

<ul>
<li>What do you and your co-founder(s) hope to get out of this business?</li>
<li>How will you know if you’ve achieved your goals?</li>
<li>If you don’t agree on the same goals, how will you know when you’ve achieved them?</li>
</ul>


<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Discussing these issues with your co-founder could get uncomfortable, create rifts, or even uncover deal-breakers. If you are able to successfully have these difficult conversations, this is a testament to your partnership and to the strength of your relationship &mdash; and will serve as a solid foundation from which to grow your business.&rdquo; &ndash; David Ehrenberg</p></blockquote>

<h3>Working Styles and Culture</h3>

<p>Once you and your cofounder have laid down the aspirational and philosophical groundwork for your startup, this is also the ideal time to determine what kind of working environment best complements the vision of your startup.</p>

<ul>
<li>What 3 words best describe the startup culture you want to create (e.g. open, hard-working, eccentric, etc.)? Pro-tip: If you’re really serious and far along go visit few office spaces together to get a sense of what each of you likes work environments wise and why.</li>
<li>What values do we want to instill in our employees?</li>
<li>If you could pick 2 things to change about our company, and two things to bring with you from your previous experience, what would they be and why?</li>
<li>How much equity are we allocating for future employees?</li>
<li>What should we look for in our first 5 hires?</li>
<li>Describe your ideal working style.</li>
</ul>


<h1>Legal Decisions &amp; Definitions</h1>

<h3>General Questions</h3>

<ul>
<li>Is the percentage ownership subject to vesting based on continued participation in the business?</li>
<li>If one founder leaves, does the company or the other founder have the right to buy back that founder’s shares? At what price?=</li>
<li>What salaries (if any), are the founders entitled to? How can that be changed?</li>
<li>How are key decisions and day-to-day decisions of the business to be made?</li>
</ul>


<h3>Basic Legal Definitions</h3>

<p>Harroch&rsquo;s article also explores numerous basic legal terms associated with launching a startup, all of which you and your business partner should familiarize yourselves with.</p>

<ul>
<li>Confidentiality Agreements &ndash; These are also referred to as Non-Disclosure Agreements or NDAs. The purpose of the agreement is to allow the holder of confidential information to share it with a third party.</li>
<li>Copyright &ndash; A copyright gives the owner the exclusive right to make copies of the work and to prepare derivative works (such as sequels or revisions) based on the work.</li>
<li>General Partnership &ndash; If there is more than one founder, a general partnership is often chosen as the legal form of business entity.</li>
<li>Patent &ndash; A patent gives its inventor the right to prevent others from making, using, or selling the patented subjected matter described in words in the patent’s claims.</li>
<li>Service marks &ndash; Service marks resemble trademarks and are used to identify services.</li>
<li>Tax Incentive &ndash; Depending on the nature of the business, various tax incentives may be available, such as renewable energy tax credits and investment tax credits.</li>
<li>Trademark &ndash; A trademark right protects the symbolic value of a word, name, symbol, or device that the trademark owner used to identify or distinguish its good from those of others.</li>
<li>Trade Secret &ndash; A trade secret right allows the owner of the right to take action against anyone who breaches an agreement or confidential relationship or who steals or uses other improper means to obtain secret information.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Include a Vesting Schedule When Issuing Shares to Co-founders</h3>

<p>When you create a vesting schedule, this means that the co-founder will earn their shares over time and protects you and the company if that a co-founder leaves the company or doesn&rsquo;t pull their weight. The standard vesting period is four years, with monthly vesting of shares. Unvested shares should be subject to repurchase by the company if the co-founder leaves the company.</p>

<h3>Protect Your Valuable Intellectual Property</h3>

<p>If intellectual property is a vital element of your business, it&rsquo;s important to protect that IP during the formative stages of a company. You can address this issue by relying on patents, trademarks, copyrights, and trade secrets to protect your valuable IP. Another step you can take is requiring all co-founders and any third-party developers to assign to the company their rights in IP they created and that is utilized by the company. Doing this will help prevent trouble if a co-founder leaves the company and takes a crucial patent with them.</p>

<h1>How to Split Equity</h1>

<h3>Ideas are Valuable</h3>

<p>If you brought the original concept to the table, increase your share holdings by about 5 percent. While execution is more important in the long run, whoever conceived the original idea deserves a little extra credit.</p>

<h3>That First Step is a Doozy</h3>

<p>Bringing something of value to the company during its formative stages – like a filed patent (not a provisional), a compelling demo, an early version of the product, or something else that means much of the work towards financing or revenue is already done – you should receive a considerable part of the equity.</p>

<h3>Full Time Commitment is Expensive</h3>

<p>Bottom line, if you’re working more, then you’re risking a lot more if the project fails, which means that you are entitled to more if the project succeeds. Also, keep in mind that part-time cofounders are a big minus to someone considering an investment, so choose your partners wisely.</p>

<h3>The CEO Gets More. Always.</h3>

<p>Splitting equity equally means that no one controls the company more than anyone else. But if that’s the case, than having a CEO is useless, as well as having any form of upper management. So, whoever is the designated CEO should get another slightly more equity. If you think that’s unfair, remember that market rate for a great CEO is higher than market rate for a great CTO, which means that’s how it is everywhere.</p>

<h3>Reputation Counts</h3>

<p>If you’re a beginning entrepreneur and your partner is an experienced founder with an established reputation, they deserve more equity. If that founder has an expansive network that benefits the company, they deserve more equity. If that founder can help secure more funding for your company, they deserve more equity.</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;The question of equity brings out the most fundamental differences, perceptions, and values in an aspiring startup. In fact the equity question, more than any other, may strangle a young company before it can even get started. And that’s a damn good thing.&rdquo; &ndash; Dan Shapiro</p></blockquote>

<h1>Final Thoughts</h1>

<p>Yes, talking about such topics as company roles and vision and equity and the like can be uncomfortable among founders. However, these discussions are vital to a successful partnership, as well as a successful startup, and must be held before any of you invest too much time, energy, and money into a potential company. Keep in mind that whoever you decide to launch a company with, you all will have to make countless difficult decisions once your company is actually up and running. If you take nothing else from this blog post, at least follow the bit of advice below:</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Choose co-founders the way you would choose a spouse. The reality is that you will, at least in the early days, spend far more time with your co-founders than your partner.&rdquo; &ndash; Danielle Newnham</p></blockquote>

<h4>Source: <a href="https://fi.co/insight/how-to-create-the-perfect-cofounder-agreement-with-your-business-partner">fi.co</a></h4>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to contribute to tech community]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/how-to-contribute-to-tech-community/"/>
    <updated>2017-10-20T01:23:01+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/how-to-contribute-to-tech-community</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Even though Vietnam is one of the booming countries for tech talents, there is still a whole gap between top developers around the world and us. Most of the points are related to how professional we are, our collaboration skill or soft skill.</p>

<p>Being a part of the tech community, realizing a few issues, also wanting to contribute a bit, this blog post is my precious and is a part of the whole series to improve the quality of next generation of developers.</p>

<p>Below is the short list of recommended things to do to contribute to the tech community.</p>

<h2>Start by listening</h2>

<p>Walking into a project and saying “Hi, here’s what I think this project should be doing” is usually not taken as a good thing. Some projects may welcome that sort of approach, but if the project has been running a while, the chances of that attitude being embraced are small. Listening is the best way to know what the project needs.</p>

<p><strong>Join a mailing list</strong></p>

<p>For a large scale and open project or community that involve many people, communication through a mailing list is one of the most effective ways to not distract others and good for you to follow the entire discussion.</p>

<p>Some of the mailing lists I followed over the past two years.</p>

<ul>
<li>Viet Infosec</li>
<li>golang-dev</li>
<li>golang-nuts</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Follow a blog</strong></p>

<p>Elite developers blog are great knowledge sources that you should follow and learn from them. Some of the rock stars they don’t have their blog. Instead, they use Twitter for daily updates.</p>

<ul>
<li>Dave Cheney: <a href="https://dave.cheney.net">Dave Cheney | The acme of foolishness</a></li>
<li>Dan Luu: <a href="https://danluu.com">Dan Luu</a></li>
<li>Rob Pike: <a href="https://commandcenter.blogspot.com">command center</a></li>
<li>Golang: <a href="https://blog.golang.org">The Go Programming Language Blog</a></li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2017-10-20-golang.png"></p>

<p><strong>Join online discussions via Slack or IRC</strong></p>

<p>Most of the communities have their channel to keep in touch and discuss the project or things related to the community with other members.</p>

<p>IRC is one of the most popular tools that have been used by many projects, e.g. Python, PostgreSQL, OpenStack. IRC is free software. You need to download a client and ask for the node address to log in.</p>

<p>Beside IRC, there are several modern communication platforms. They are commercial products that serve the teamwork very well. Some with a free plan has been applied to the new community: Gitter, Slack, Discord. Also, new members are always welcome there.</p>

<ul>
<li>Reactiflux: <a href="https://discordapp.com/invite/reactiflux">Discord</a></li>
<li>Golang: <a href="https://gophers.slack.com">Slack</a></li>
<li>Sails: <a href="https://gitter.im/balderdashy/sails">balderdashy/sails &ndash; Gitter</a></li>
</ul>


<p>Some communities in Vietnam I take participation in</p>

<ul>
<li>Golang Vietnam: <a href="http://golang.org.vn">http://golang.org.vn</a></li>
<li>Ruby Vietnam: <a href="http://ruby.org.vn">http://ruby.org.vn</a></li>
<li>Grokking Engineering: <a href="http://grokking.net">http://grokking.net</a></li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2017-10-20-golang-slack.png"></p>

<h2>Participating</h2>

<p><strong>Organizing events</strong></p>

<p>The event organizer is a difficult job and very time consuming, but it’s the most critical factor to keep the community alive. People might not find it necessary as it depends on the interest. During the days in 201x, more and more events were held by the various scale of organizations and companies. Some activities that you may find</p>

<ul>
<li>Technical Meetup (Golang, Ruby, Geeky, Grokking)</li>
<li>Product Meetup</li>
<li>Design Workshop</li>
<li>Mobile Day</li>
<li>Web Summit</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2017-10-20-websummit.png"></p>

<p><strong>Sponsor an Event</strong></p>

<p>Sponsoring a participant in a program can be a great way to show your support, especially when you have your friends or employees participating in that event.</p>

<p>Usual the local events are just at a small scale from 50 &ndash; 100 participants. If they are meetup or workshop event, most of their needs are a venue to organize or food and beverage or a small amount of money for operating costs.</p>

<p><strong>Sharing your knowledge</strong></p>

<p>In every event, if you can’t afford to sponsor an event or have enough time to be an organizing member, you still can give your hand to the community by sharing your thoughts, your knowledge to other people.</p>

<p><strong>Answer a question</strong>
The best way to help build the community is by helping others. Answering someone questions especially when he is just getting his feet wet is very helpful for him. I see a lot Viet Community doesn’t have that culture. They usually piss off the newbies and don’t want to give out their hands.</p>

<p><strong>Write a blog post</strong></p>

<p>If you’ve got a blog, write about your experiences with the project that you’re using. Tell about a problem you faced utilizing the software and what you did to solve it. You’ll be helping in two ways, both by helping keep the project on the minds of others around you and by creating a record for anyone else who has your problem in the future and searches the web for the answer.</p>

<h3>Contributing to Open Source</h3>

<p>Open source software (OSS) is distributed under a licensing agreement which allows computer code to be shared, viewed and modified by other users and organizations.</p>

<p>Alternatively, in slightly more user-friendly language, open source software is available for the general public to use and modify from its original design free of charge. What it means is that a piece of software can evolve and be iterated upon by other developers anywhere in the world. Ideally, this says that the software is improved over time, but it can often take plenty of exciting twists and turns with all of that evolution and can change form and shape entirely. <sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup></p>

<p><strong>Diagnose a bug</strong></p>

<p>Bugs are often poorly reported. Building an attitude to help narrow down the problem make it easier for the developers to fix it. Whatever you discover, add it to the ticket in the bug system for all to see.</p>

<p><strong>Fix a bug</strong></p>

<p>Finding an interesting bug in the ticket system and try to fix it is the best practical way to contribute to the open source project. Remember to follow the guideline and during your working period, document whatever you know to help the later contributors. Write some tests if you can.</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2017-10-20-issue.png"></p>

<p><strong>Write a test</strong></p>

<p>Adding the test to the open source project will help to improve the quality and make it more stable. In some cases, test cases and test suites are more like the documents for the project.</p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open-source_software<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The CEO roles: Idea to Continuous Growth]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/the-ceo-roles-idea-to-continuous-growth/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-17T12:37:33+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/the-ceo-roles-idea-to-continuous-growth</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A CEO role must evolve to sustain growth. Where are you in the growth journey?</p>

<h1>Start Up</h1>

<p>Here CEOs are:</p>

<ul>
<li>Doers, the &lsquo;Jacks and Janes&rsquo; of all trades.</li>
<li>Decision makers</li>
</ul>


<h1>Initial Growth</h1>

<p>CEOs must:</p>

<ul>
<li>Learn to delegate</li>
<li>Learn how to attract and recruit the right people</li>
<li>Set the company direction</li>
</ul>


<h1>Rapid Growth</h1>

<p>CEOs need to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Hire people with more knowledge than themselves in the key business functions</li>
<li>Get the team to function as a &lsquo;team&rsquo;, to plan and communicate</li>
</ul>


<h1>Continuous Growth</h1>

<p>CEOs need to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Become strategic innovators &amp; change catalysts</li>
<li>Lead the company culture</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2016-09-17-ceo-roles.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Sleep Revolution Manifesto]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/the-sleep-revolution-manifesto/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-17T12:11:43+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/the-sleep-revolution-manifesto</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The below manifesto is excerp from the book. Reading them carefully help me a lot. Work &amp; Life balance is always a nice &amp; endless topic.</p>

<ol>
<li>Sleep is a fundamental and non-negotiable human need.</li>
<li>Sleep allows us to see the world with fresh eyes and a reinvigorated spirit.</li>
<li>We may be what we eat, but also, to be sure, we are how we sleep.</li>
<li>Exhaustion is a sign of chaos, not a badge of honor.</li>
<li>A good day starts the night before.</li>
<li>We will treat ourselves as well as we treat our smartphones, making sure we sleep until fully recharged.</li>
<li>A bedroom should be an oasis: a beautiful, relaxing escape from the demands of the day.</li>
<li>We will usher our smartphones out of the bedroom when we go to bed.</li>
<li>We will not drive if we are drowsy!</li>
<li>We will choose Ògoing-to-bed clothes,&ldquo; not to be confused with Ògoing-to-the-gym clothes.&rdquo; Pajamas, nightdresses, and even special T-shirts send a sleep-friendly signal to our bodies: time to shut down!</li>
<li>We will choose sleep over busywork.</li>
<li>When we walk through the door of our bedroom, we will leave the day–with all of its problems and unfinished business–behind.</li>
</ol>


<h4>Source: <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sleep-Revolution-Transforming-Your-Night/dp/110190402X">Sleep Revolution</a></h4>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git practices at Dwarves Foundation]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/git-practices-at-dwarves-foundation/"/>
    <updated>2016-06-20T04:32:09+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/git-practices-at-dwarves-foundation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Git is one of the most popular source control. Github is one platform built over the top of Git and well adapted by lots of companies. Knowing the right workflow will help to increase team productivity. In this post, I will try to cover some of the best practices from the community and the way we applied them at <a href="https://www.dwarves.foundation">Dwarves Foundation</a>.</p>

<h1>Know how to write good commit message</h1>

<blockquote><p>Source: <a href="http://chris.beams.io/posts/git-commit/">http://chris.beams.io/posts/git-commit/</a></p></blockquote>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2016-06-27-git-commit.png"></p>

<p>Have you ever read some repos with commit messages like above?</p>

<p>While many repositories&#8217; logs look like the former, there are exceptions. The <a href="https://github.com/torvalds/linux/commits/master">Linux kernel</a> and <a href="https://github.com/git/git/commits/master">git itself</a> are great examples. Look at <a href="https://github.com/spring-projects/spring-boot/commits/master">Spring Boot</a>, or any repository managed by <a href="https://github.com/tpope/vim-pathogen/commits/master">Tim Pope</a>. The contributors to these repositories know that a well-crafted git commit message is the best way to communicate context about a change to fellow developers (and indeed to their future selves). A diff will tell you what changed, but only the commit message can properly tell you why.</p>

<p>Being known that, a project&rsquo;s long-term success rests (among other things) on its maintainability, reviewing others commits and pull requests is also the big reason that you should write great commit messages.</p>

<p>In the post, the author wants to address the most basic elements of keeping a healthy commit history: how to write an individual commit message. You can checkout the source article or just follow the <strong>seven rules</strong> below and you&rsquo;re on your way to committing like a pro</p>

<ol>
<li>Separate subject from body with a blank line</li>
<li>Limit the subject line to 50 characters</li>
<li>Capitalize the subject line</li>
<li>Do not end the subject line with a period</li>
<li>Use the imperative mood in the subject line</li>
<li>Wrap the body at 72 characters</li>
<li>Use the body to explain what and why vs. how</li>
</ol>


<h1>Git branching model</h1>

<h1>Gitflow</h1>

<p>Inspired by Vincent Driessen&rsquo;s branching model, git-flow are a set of git extensions to provide high-level repository operations for it. Git-flow is a merge based solution. It doesn&rsquo;t rebase feature branches.</p>

<ul>
<li>Checkout gitflow cheatsheet: <a href="http://danielkummer.github.io/git-flow-cheatsheet/">http://danielkummer.github.io/git-flow-cheatsheet/</a></li>
<li>Apps that support gitflow:

<ul>
<li>Source Tree: <a href="https://www.sourcetreeapp.com">https://www.sourcetreeapp.com</a></li>
<li>Git Tower: <a href="https://www.git-tower.com">https://www.git-tower.com</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>Note: Maybe after working for a long time with merge based Gitflow, you will find your git log a little bit confusing and look like that:</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2016-06-27-gitflow-mess.png"></p>

<p>Please take no worries about this, because there is still a part about <code>git rebase</code>. For now, you can continue to read the article <a href="http://endoflineblog.com/gitflow-considered-harmful">GitFlow considered harmful</a> to know more about the author issue.</p>

<h3>Gitflow pitfall</h3>

<ul>
<li>It makes the project&rsquo;s history completely unreadable with the <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/9069061/what-is-the-difference-between-git-merge-and-git-merge-no-ff"><code>--no-ff</code> flag</a>. The &mdash;no-ff flag prevents git merge from executing a &ldquo;fast-forward&rdquo; if it detects that your current HEAD is an ancestor of the commit you&rsquo;re trying to merge. A fast-forward is when, instead of constructing a merge commit, git just moves your branch pointer to point at the incoming commit.</li>
<li>The master/develop split is redundant.</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s needlessly complex. And people make mistakes and break them by accident.</li>
</ul>


<h3>The Anti-gitflow</h3>

<ul>
<li>There is only one eternal branch &ndash; you can call it master, develop, current, next &ndash; whatever. I personally like &ldquo;master&rdquo;, and that&rsquo;s the name I&rsquo;ll use in the rest of the description, as it&rsquo;s convention by now in the Git world and immediately conveys its purpose.</li>
<li>All other branches (feature, release, hotfix, and whatever else you need) are temporary and only used as a convenience to share code with other developers and as a backup measure. They are always removed once the changes present on them land on master.</li>
<li>Features are integrated onto the master branch primarily in a way which keeps the history linear. You have a lot of leeway in how you want to enforce this. You can make it simply a convention that developers are encouraged, but not forced, to follow. On the other side of the spectrum, if you use something like Gerrit to manage your Git repositories (which I recommend, even if you don&rsquo;t practice code reviews &ndash; the permission system is fantastic, and if you ever decide you want code reviews, it&rsquo;ll be very easy to start doing them), you can set up permissions in such a way that actually forbids pushing merge commits to master, and that way ensure linear history.</li>
<li>Releases are done similarly to in GitFlow. You create a new branch for the release, branching off at the point in master that you decide has all the necessary features. From then on new work, aimed for the next release, is pushed to master as always, and any necessary changes are pushed to the release branch (in my opinion, it&rsquo;s an anti-pattern and a huge red flag if your release requires separate commits to work, but that&rsquo;s a topic for another article &ndash; for simplicity, let&rsquo;s assume you can&rsquo;t or don&rsquo;t want to change that). Finally, once the release is ready, you tag the top of the release branch. Then, because there is one eternal branch, there is only one way to get your release to be versioned permanently &ndash; and that is to merge the release branch into master and push that changed master. After that, all the changes that were made during the release are now part of master, and the release branch is deleted.</li>
<li>Hotfixes are very similar to releases, except you don&rsquo;t branch from an arbitrary commit on master, but from the release tag that you want to make the fix in. Again, work on master continues as always, and the necessary fixes are pushed to the hotfix branch. Once the fix is ready, the procedure is exactly the same as for a release &ndash; tag the top of the branch creating a new release, merge it into master, then delete the hotfix branch.</li>
</ul>


<h1>Pull Request</h1>

<p>Pull request is a feature that makes it easier for developers to collaborate. Pull request is a mechanism for a developer to notify team members that they have completed a feature. Some tricks to make Pull Requests more awesome for your project:</p>

<ul>
<li>Open a Pull Request as early as possible: Pull Requests are a great way to start a conversation of a feature, so start one as soon as possible- even before you are finished with the code. Your team can comment on the feature as it evolves, instead of providing all their feedback at the very end.</li>
<li>Pull Requests work branch to branch: No one has a fork of github/github. We make Pull Requests in the same repository by opening Pull Requests for branches.</li>
<li>A Pull Request doesn&rsquo;t have to be merged: Pull Requests are easy to make and a great way to get feedback and track progress on a branch. But some ideas don&rsquo;t make it. It&rsquo;s okay to close a Pull Request without merging; we do it all the time.</li>
</ul>


<p>Hint: Based on an article <a href="http://ben.balter.com/2015/12/08/types-of-pull-requests/">Type of Pull Request</a>, there are 6 types of PR. But <a href="http://ben.straub.cc/2015/04/02/wip-pull-request/"><code>WIP pattern</code></a> is the one that is using by lots of teams and companies. It follows the mantra of &ldquo;<strong>Open a Pull Request as early as possible</strong>&rdquo;.</p>

<h1>Doing Code Review</h1>

<blockquote><p>Source: <a href="https://github.com/thoughtbot/guides/tree/master/code-review">https://github.com/thoughtbot/guides/tree/master/code-review</a></p></blockquote>

<h3>Everyone</h3>

<ul>
<li>Accept that many programming decisions are opinions. Discuss tradeoffs, which you prefer, and reach a resolution quickly.</li>
<li>Ask questions; don&rsquo;t make demands. (&ldquo;What do you think about naming this :user_id?&rdquo;)</li>
<li>Ask for clarification. (&ldquo;I didn&rsquo;t understand. Can you clarify?&rdquo;)</li>
<li>Avoid selective ownership of code. (&ldquo;mine&rdquo;, &ldquo;not mine&rdquo;, &ldquo;yours&rdquo;)</li>
<li>Avoid using terms that could be seen as referring to personal traits. (&ldquo;dumb&rdquo;, &ldquo;stupid&rdquo;). Assume everyone is attractive, &ndash; intelligent, and well-meaning.</li>
<li>Be explicit. Remember people don&rsquo;t always understand your intentions online.</li>
<li>Be humble. (&ldquo;I&rsquo;m not sure &ndash; let&rsquo;s look it up.&rdquo;)</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t use hyperbole. (&ldquo;always&rdquo;, &ldquo;never&rdquo;, &ldquo;endlessly&rdquo;, &ldquo;nothing&rdquo;)</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t use sarcasm.</li>
<li>Keep it real. If emoji, animated gifs, or humor aren&rsquo;t you, don&rsquo;t force them. If they are, use them with aplomb.</li>
<li>Talk synchronously (e.g. chat, screensharing, in person) if there are too many &ldquo;I didn&rsquo;t understand&rdquo; or &ldquo;Alternative solution:&rdquo; comments. Post a follow-up comment summarizing the discussion.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Having Your Code Reviewed</h3>

<ul>
<li>Be grateful for the reviewer&rsquo;s suggestions. (&ldquo;Good call. I&rsquo;ll make that change.&rdquo;)</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t take it personally. The review is of the code, not you.</li>
<li>Explain why the code exists. (&ldquo;It&rsquo;s like that because of these reasons. Would it be more clear if I rename this class/file/&ndash; method/variable?&rdquo;)</li>
<li>Extract some changes and refactorings into future tickets/stories.</li>
<li>Link to the code review from the ticket/story. (&ldquo;Ready for review: <a href="https://github.com/organization/project/pull/1">https://github.com/organization/project/pull/1</a>&rdquo;)</li>
<li>Push commits based on earlier rounds of feedback as isolated commits to the branch. Do not squash until the branch is ready &ndash; to merge. Reviewers should be able to read individual updates based on their earlier feedback.</li>
<li>Seek to understand the reviewer&rsquo;s perspective.</li>
<li>Try to respond to every comment.</li>
<li>Wait to merge the branch until Continuous Integration tells you the test suite is green in the &ndash; branch.</li>
<li>Merge once you feel confident in the code and its impact on the project.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Reviewing code</h3>

<p>Understand why the change is necessary (fixes a bug, improves the user experience, refactors the existing code). Then:</p>

<ul>
<li>Communicate which ideas you feel strongly about and those you don&rsquo;t.</li>
<li>Identify ways to simplify the code while still solving the problem.</li>
<li>If discussions turn too philosophical or academic, move the discussion offline to a regular Friday afternoon technique &ndash; discussion. In the meantime, let the author make the final decision on alternative implementations.</li>
<li>Offer alternative implementations, but assume the author already considered them. (&ldquo;What do you think about using a custom &ndash; validator here?&rdquo;)</li>
<li>Seek to understand the author&rsquo;s perspective.</li>
<li>Sign off on the pull request with a 👍 or &ldquo;Ready to merge&rdquo; comment.</li>
</ul>


<h1>Git templates</h1>

<p>To make things easier, we have adopted Issue template and Pull Request template that we think they are great to help the team to improve the productivity</p>

<blockquote><p><a href="https://gist.githubusercontent.com/tieubao/2a9fc10be45a67ab315ef3f8ead6530d/raw/e99d04268bf83389f4f728f386f79d9da3132480/issue-template.md">https://gist.githubusercontent.com/tieubao/2a9fc10be45a67ab315ef3f8ead6530d/raw/e99d04268bf83389f4f728f386f79d9da3132480/issue-template.md</a></p></blockquote>

<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/2a9fc10be45a67ab315ef3f8ead6530d.js'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>&lt;!--
Please use the following template to submit your issue. Following this template will allow us to quickly investigate and help you with your issue. Please be aware that issues which do not conform to this template may be closed.
--&gt;

### Status

BUG REPORT / TASK

### Checklist

Add checklist if this is a task

- [x] Add Facebook login
- [ ] Support X

### Steps to reproduce

1. First step
2. Second step
3. Third step

### Expected behaviour

How do you think the program should work? Add screenshots and code blocks if necessary.

### Actual behaviour

How does the program work in its current state?

### Environment

You may write here the specifications like the version of the project, operating system, or hardware if applicable.

### Logs / Stack trace

```
Insert your log/stack trace here
```

</code></pre></noscript></div>


<blockquote><p><a href="https://gist.githubusercontent.com/tieubao/98a83f179d06fe3e33e4dfe4f1395904/raw/4cd5eaa3586503c9a89b7cac34886e2769db01d1/pr-template.md">https://gist.githubusercontent.com/tieubao/98a83f179d06fe3e33e4dfe4f1395904/raw/4cd5eaa3586503c9a89b7cac34886e2769db01d1/pr-template.md</a></p></blockquote>

<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/98a83f179d06fe3e33e4dfe4f1395904.js'></script>
<noscript><pre><code>&lt;!--
This is a guide to use this Pull Request Template
&gt; DELETE THIS BLOCK TO AFTER READING

# Title
- Put [WIP] in front of the Pull Request that you are working on
- Clear [WIP] after you completed and ping the reviewer

# Body
- You have to fill out all the sections
- Delete or put N/A if the section is nil
--&gt;

#### Status

READY / IN DEVELOPMENT / HOLD

#### What does this PR accomplish?

- [x] Adds a shiny new button
- [ ] Fixed serious memory leak
- [ ] ...

#### Where should the reviewer start?

#### How should this be manually tested?

#### Any background context you want to provide?

#### What are the relevant Git tickets?

Use [Github closing words](https://help.github.com/articles/closing-issues-via-commit-messages/) such as:  
This closes #x

#### Screenshots (if appropriate)

#### Questions:

- Is there a blog post?
- Does the knowledge base need an update?
- Does this add new dependencies which need to be added to?
</code></pre></noscript></div>




<br>


<hr />

<p><sup>And finally, Atlassian has a full tutorials from scratch, you can find it at: <a href="https://www.atlassian.com/git/tutorials/what-is-version-control">https://www.atlassian.com/git/tutorials/what-is-version-control</a><sup></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How we contribute to Homebrew]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/how-we-contribute-to-homebrew/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-13T10:35:21+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/how-we-contribute-to-homebrew</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Homebrew</h2>

<p>Homebrew (or brew) is one of the biggest repo on Github with more than 29k stars, 14k forks and 1k watches. It was started by Max Howell in 2009 to build the missing package manager for OS X. Back to before 2009, in Mac OSX, if we wanted to install something, we had to install it via pkg files or bin files. We didn&rsquo;t have anything fancy like <code>apt-get</code> in Ubuntu or <code>yum</code> in Fedora. MacPort was an only option but it was not too good. Check the very old article about it: <a href="http://www.engadget.com/2009/12/25/homebrew-the-perfect-gift-for-command-line-lovers/">Homebrew, the perfect gift for command line lovers</a></p>

<p>For now, you can access homebrew via</p>

<ul>
<li>Homepage: <a href="http://brew.sh">http://brew.sh</a></li>
<li>Github: <a href="https://github.com/Homebrew/homebrew">https://github.com/Homebrew/homebrew</a></li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2016-03-13-homebrew.png"></p>

<p>To install homebrew, you just need to run the ruby script and you will get <code>brew</code> command ready in couple of minutes.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>/usr/bin/ruby -e "$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/master/install)"</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Homebrew is developed in Ruby and its program will be defined as a formula which is simple Ruby script. Most of tools can be found in Homebrew such as: docker, ruby, python, ansible, todo.txt, &hellip; At this time they have over 3k5 formulas that was contributed by community.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>class Wget &lt; Formula
</span><span class='line'>  homepage "https://www.gnu.org/software/wget/"
</span><span class='line'>  url "https://ftp.gnu.org/gnu/wget/wget-1.15.tar.gz"
</span><span class='line'>  sha256 "52126be8cf1bddd7536886e74c053ad7d0ed2aa89b4b630f76785bac21695fcd"
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  def install
</span><span class='line'>    system "./configure", "--prefix=#{prefix}"
</span><span class='line'>    system "make", "install"
</span><span class='line'>  end
</span><span class='line'>end</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Simple use cases for Homebrew after you got it:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>// $FORMULA is the name of your formula
</span><span class='line'>$ brew install $FORMULA</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Brew makes it really easy to update and upgrade. Because everything is based on Git, you just need to run those below commands then everything will be done automatically.</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>$ brew update
</span><span class='line'>$ brew upgrade</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h2>How to contribute to Homebrew</h2>

<p>Note: In this post, we just cover the command line or tool part of Homebrew. The example is taken from our <a href="https://github.com/dwarvesf/glod-cli"><strong>glod-cli</strong></a></p>

<p>When you look into the repo of Homebrew, you can easily find the doc directory in <code>homebrew/share/doc/homebrew/</code> which contains all the information. The most important file for this tutorial is the <code>Formula-Cookbook.md</code>.</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2016-03-13-homebrew-doc.png"></p>

<p>Basically, when you use homebrew, it will create a separate folder on your machine. Everything usually will be installed in <code>/usr/local/Cellar</code> and all formulas was stored at <code>/usr/local/Library/Formula</code>.</p>

<p>So in short, if you want to contribute a new one, you need to create a new formula in your local and submit a pull request to <code>https://github.com/Homebrew/homebrew</code>.</p>

<h3>Fork from homebrew</h3>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2016-03-13-homebrew.png"></p>

<p>For us, we will have a repo called <code>dwarvesf/homebrew</code> which we can clone and start from there.</p>

<h3>Create new formula</h3>

<p>Make sure you have installed <code>brew</code> on your machine (you have to!) and your new formula must meets all their <a href="https://github.com/Homebrew/homebrew/blob/master/share/doc/homebrew/Acceptable-Formulae.md">Acceptable Formulae</a> requirements.</p>

<p>Then we can start from create a new branch (like git workflow) or not. For us we skip it and use the master branch (plot twist: we forgot to do this step)</p>

<p>We move to the step of create new formula by run the command</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>$ brew create &lt;URL.tar.gz&gt;</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Example for us, we use the archive url of our github repo <code>https://github.com/dwarvesf/glod-cli/archive/1.0.3.2.tar.gz</code>. You can get it by combining</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>https://github.com/&lt;YOUR REPO&gt;/archive/&lt;COMMIT SHA | TAG&gt;.tar.gz</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>This command will help to create a local formula in <code>/usr/local/Library/Formula</code> and open with your default $EDITOR. You have to write a small Ruby script to <code>install</code> and <code>test</code> the formula. You can refer to other formulas to make it easier. Check out the main repo <code>https://github.com/Homebrew/homebrew/tree/master/Library/Formula</code> or the forked one. If you have Go formula like us, you can easily search for more than 100 existed Go formulas. It&rsquo;s a great source for references.</p>

<p>Our formula looks like this</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
<span class='line-number'>14</span>
<span class='line-number'>15</span>
<span class='line-number'>16</span>
<span class='line-number'>17</span>
<span class='line-number'>18</span>
<span class='line-number'>19</span>
<span class='line-number'>20</span>
<span class='line-number'>21</span>
<span class='line-number'>22</span>
<span class='line-number'>23</span>
<span class='line-number'>24</span>
<span class='line-number'>25</span>
<span class='line-number'>26</span>
<span class='line-number'>27</span>
<span class='line-number'>28</span>
<span class='line-number'>29</span>
<span class='line-number'>30</span>
<span class='line-number'>31</span>
<span class='line-number'>32</span>
<span class='line-number'>33</span>
<span class='line-number'>34</span>
<span class='line-number'>35</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="nb">require</span> <span class="s2">&quot;language/go&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">class</span> <span class="nc">GlodCli</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span> <span class="no">Formula</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">desc</span> <span class="s2">&quot;Glod command-line interface tools&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">homepage</span> <span class="s2">&quot;https://github.com/dwarvesf/glod-cli&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">url</span> <span class="s2">&quot;https://github.com/dwarvesf/glod-cli/archive/1.0.3.2.tar.gz&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">sha256</span> <span class="s2">&quot;1826e8b5398f10a12d5f315a9f5a670f05ac3e0f6ead7c4edddf621c2260ae6c&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">depends_on</span> <span class="s2">&quot;go&quot;</span> <span class="o">=&gt;</span> <span class="ss">:build</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">depends_on</span> <span class="s2">&quot;godep&quot;</span> <span class="o">=&gt;</span> <span class="ss">:build</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="n">go_resource</span> <span class="s2">&quot;github.com/kr/fs&quot;</span> <span class="k">do</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">url</span> <span class="s2">&quot;https://github.com/kr/fs.git&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="ss">:revision</span> <span class="o">=&gt;</span> <span class="s2">&quot;2788f0dbd16903de03cb8186e5c7d97b69ad387b&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">end</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">install</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="no">ENV</span><span class="o">[</span><span class="s2">&quot;GOPATH&quot;</span><span class="o">]</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">buildpath</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="no">ENV</span><span class="o">[</span><span class="s2">&quot;GO15VENDOREXPERIMENT&quot;</span><span class="o">]</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s2">&quot;0&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">mkdir_p</span> <span class="n">buildpath</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="s2">&quot;src/github.com/dwarvesf/&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">ln_s</span> <span class="n">buildpath</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">buildpath</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="s2">&quot;src/github.com/dwarvesf/glod-cli&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="ss">Language</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="ss">:Go</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">stage_deps</span> <span class="n">resources</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">buildpath</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="s2">&quot;src&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nb">system</span> <span class="s2">&quot;godep&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;go&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;build&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;-o&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;glod-cli&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;.&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">bin</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">install</span> <span class="s2">&quot;glod-cli&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">end</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="nb">test</span> <span class="k">do</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">output</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">shell_output</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">bin</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="s2">&quot;glod-cli --version&quot;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">assert_match</span> <span class="s2">&quot;glod-cli version </span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="n">version</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="se">\n</span><span class="s2">&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">output</span>
</span><span class='line'>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nb">system</span> <span class="n">bin</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="s2">&quot;glod-cli&quot;</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="s2">&quot;http://mp3.zing.vn/bai-hat/Hello-Vietnam-Pham-Quynh-Anh/ZWZ9C8EB.html&quot;</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="nb">sleep</span> <span class="mi">2</span>
</span><span class='line'>    <span class="n">assert</span> <span class="no">File</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">exist?</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s2">&quot;Hello Vietnam.mp3&quot;</span><span class="p">)</span>
</span><span class='line'>  <span class="k">end</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="k">end</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h3>Install / Debug local formula</h3>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="err">$</span> <span class="n">brew</span> <span class="n">install</span> <span class="o">--</span><span class="n">verbose</span> <span class="o">--</span><span class="n">debug</span> <span class="vg">$FORMULA</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>This command will help to install your formula at <code>/usr/local/Library/Formula</code>. Happy debugging until you can install it smoothly.</p>

<p>Sometimes you will need to uninstall the formula, you can use this command</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="err">$</span> <span class="n">brew</span> <span class="n">unlink</span> <span class="vg">$FORMULA</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="err">$</span> <span class="n">brew</span> <span class="n">cleanup</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<h3>Test the formula</h3>

<p>One note for the test block, there are still a lot of formula that try to cheat by printing out the help or version. As a good contributor, you should write good tests for your formulas or your pull request will be rejected (like us)</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2016-03-13-homebrew-failed-test.png"></p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="err">$</span> <span class="n">brew</span> <span class="nb">test</span> <span class="vg">$FORMULA</span>
</span><span class='line'><span class="err">$</span> <span class="n">brew</span> <span class="n">audit</span> <span class="o">--</span><span class="n">strict</span> <span class="o">--</span><span class="n">online</span> <span class="vg">$FORMULA</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Those tests should be passed to make sure your formula is qualified. The second command is provided to check if your formula have</p>

<ul>
<li>More than 50 stars</li>
<li>More than 20 forks</li>
<li>More than 20 watchers</li>
<li>And initialized more than 30 days</li>
</ul>


<h3>Submit pull request</h3>

<p>Bravo! It&rsquo;s really great if you can get here, your formula is qualified. Let&rsquo;s copy the local formula to your git repo. Example</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span></span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='ruby'><span class='line'><span class="err">$</span> <span class="n">cp</span> <span class="o">-</span><span class="n">f</span> <span class="sr">/usr/</span><span class="n">local</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="no">Library</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="no">Formula</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="n">glod</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="n">cli</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">rb</span> <span class="o">~</span><span class="sr">/Workspace/</span><span class="n">dwarvesf</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="n">homebrew</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="no">Library</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="no">Formula</span>
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>Commit and push your changes to <strong>YOUR</strong> Github. Then we open the Github Repo (still yours), click on button <code>New pull request</code> and we get</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2016-03-13-homebrew-pull-request.png"></p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2016-03-13-homebrew-pull-request-02.png"></p>

<p>We did it! You only still need the feedback from Homebrew team. You can leave your keyboard and take a cup of coffee. If everything goes well, well done boss! you have just contribute to one of the famous repo in the internet. Congratulations!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go and Elixir]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/go-and-elixir/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-11T14:24:20+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/go-and-elixir</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m the founder of Dwarves Foundation, a software development firm that based in South East Asia. We use both languages in production and have developed some web apps, systems using Go and Elixir.</p>

<p>First of all, I have to say both languages are great, same as the communities. They are both concurrency languages, but there are some differences in their souls.</p>

<p>If you come from the background of Python, Go take the same approach of &lsquo;manual language.&rsquo; Go is a minimal language. Go replaces the inheritance by the composition (which said by someone &ldquo;Inheritance was a bad dream that (most) people have woken up from.&rdquo;) There is no magic in Go source code. Also, with the support of &lsquo;gofmt&rsquo; (syntax formatter), it brings you the transparency of knowledge between your source code and others. You will feel no hesitation to read the source code of your friends or open source libraries in Github.</p>

<p><strong>Go is the best fit for API services and command line tool development</strong>. Go is a &lsquo;have-to-learn&rsquo; language for engineers.</p>

<p>Go brings you the feel of &lsquo;it just works&rsquo; language after years working with it in several projects. Talking a little bit more about Go web frameworks, they do have a good framework for web development: Gin, echo, goji &hellip; are the minimal one like Flask, Express or Sinatra; Beego, Revel are full-fledged or battery included frameworks like Django, Sails or Rails. However, at the end of the day, you don&rsquo;t want to use those frameworks or ORMs at all, you will just want to use built-in components of Go to build your new system. That&rsquo;s the moment when you have been enlightened to feel the minimalism of Go. &ldquo;It just works,&rdquo; the gopher in you will speak to yourself.</p>

<p>You can take reference to <a href="https://github.com/mattermost/mattermost-server">mattermost</a> repository to learn more the stack of Go as API server and React for web front-end.</p>

<hr />

<p>After the long time working with Go and if you are the type of lazy developers, you will find that Go language itself isn&rsquo;t wise enough. Go makes sense outside of the web dev world. As a web developer, you still need the super fast speed, but you want something as cool as Rails, Elixir/Phoenix is good for you.</p>

<ul>
<li>Functional Programming vs. OOP (<a href="https://medium.com/@brianwill/object-oriented-programming-a-personal-disaster-1b044c2383ab">Object-Oriented Programming: A Disaster Story</a>)</li>
<li>Fault tolerance. It&rsquo;s something Go doesn&rsquo;t have. If an Erlang process (not an OS process, an Erlang process) dies, it dies. Every other process on the system is fine and Erlang has facilities to have processes monitor other processes and bring each other back up if one dies. It&rsquo;s just amazing. Absolutely beautiful.</li>
<li>Abstract Syntax Trees. The one that brings <strong>Homoiconicity</strong> which is believed to be the source of power of Lisp.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<p>We are soldiers. We use different guns or knives in different purposes.
At the moment, our stack is as below.</p>

<ul>
<li>Go for API server, cmd line tools, and DevOps scripts.</li>
<li>Elixir for web development.</li>
<li>Vue.js for frontend development</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Today I learned]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/today-i-learned/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-03T01:30:29+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/today-i-learned</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Continuous learning is one of my passion and I kept doing this for about 4 years. Everyday life, the knowledge bypass my brain and go thru. People write a lot of awesome stuffs on Medium, their personal blogs or HackerNews. I used to note them to Notes or Evernote before. Later I found those tools are very frustrating, hard to look up and I even did not open them again.</p>

<p>As a former CTO &amp; Tech Entrepreneur, Github is one of the most opened site of mine. With filtering and labeling features, we can easily organize our references to the articles. The labels will help you to classify the information and it&rsquo;s cool to make the search after that, easier to share with your friends, your colleagues.</p>

<p>So, I decided to note them all on Github.</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2015-12-03-til.png"></p>

<h2>Methodology</h2>

<p><em>&ldquo;Today I learned&rdquo;</em> is not the new idea, people around the world used different ways to implement the idea. If you have time, let google around and you can find some interesting topic on reddit or medium about this methodology. People call it by various name Today I/We learned, Today I found out &hellip; but the same concept is that you should keep yourself up and run. It&rsquo;s all about the productivity, the improvement of yourself. Improving yourself just 1% everyday and in a year you are better than 37.8 times.</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2015-12-03-101.jpg"></p>

<p>If you are interested in this idea, you can follow the hashtag <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/til">#til</a> on Twitter or making one and share your <strong>#til</strong> repo.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>New TIL</strong>: <a href="https://github.com/tieubao/til/issues/new">https://github.com/tieubao/til/issues/new</a></li>
<li><strong>Dashboard</strong>: <a href="https://github.com/tieubao/til/issues">https://github.com/tieubao/til/issues</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[dotfiles]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/dotfiles/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-05T03:20:06+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/dotfiles</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>The developer</h1>

<p>In linux, the files start with a dot &ldquo;.&rdquo; are hidden. If you list files in the directory, they normally don&rsquo;t show up and keep them safe from the users. Because of that reason, the developer usually use it to store configurations of their tools. Those files are so called dotfiles. The first dot file for most of us is maybe the shell configuration file (.bashrc | .bash_profile)</p>

<blockquote><p>Nowsday, you can find the dotfiles everywhere in your system.</p></blockquote>

<p>Do you use git? vim?
Do you use your ssh identities to authenticate with git server?
Do you have any env configurations or even the backup from other apps?</p>

<p>We are software developer. Our machine is more like our second home. We spend more than 8 hours per day with it. I have a friend from Singapore. Last time when I was with him drunk, I asked him for who is his gf and suddenly he pointed at his laptop. What a nerd!</p>

<p>Back to the point, as a developer, we use a lot of tools and applications that need to back up.</p>

<h1>The community</h1>

<p>Years ago, people don&rsquo;t think about back up the dotfiles. Because we spend a lot of time with the shell, so most of the time, people just value their config for the shell. There are some topics around for people to show off their shell config. But this turned out a good start of the community.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://ubuntuforums.org/showthread.php?t=679762">Show us your .bashrc!</a></li>
<li><a href="https://bbs.archlinux.org/viewtopic.php?id=41331">Share your bashrc!</a></li>
<li><p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/programming/comments/9he4v/share_your_bashrc_vimrc_or_other_settings_file_i">Share your .bashrc, .vimrc, or other settings file</a></p>

<p>  <img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2015-11-05-allias.png"></p></li>
</ul>


<p>After a few years, technology changed really fast and bring developers lots of useful tools like homebrew, z, logcat-color, &hellip; Developers use different tech stacks and they have their own setting for the workspace. Once they change the workspace or move from machine to machine, it takes so many hours to setup again. That&rsquo;s why some guys start to think about all their dotfiles and back up their workspace config.</p>

<p>If you are new for dotfiles, you can have a quick look at: <a href="https://dotfiles.github.io.">https://dotfiles.github.io.</a> They organise most popular dotfiles for you to look at or start with. You can browse some repo to learn from the community, discover new tools for your toolbox and new tricks for the ones you already use.</p>

<h1>Mine</h1>

<p>I&rsquo;m a geek and a tech entreprenuer. I&rsquo;m also the founder of Dwarves Foundation. We offer venture builder service and a strong tech team to help people build their tech company.</p>

<p>I began to care about my dotfiles for a year. You can find it around Github @ <a href="https://github.com/tieubao/dotfiles">tieubao/dotfiles</a></p>

<p>And you can find my dotfiles helpful if you are using the same stack as me:</p>

<ul>
<li>OSX user</li>
<li>Install stuffs via homebrew</li>
<li>Editor: vim (or sublime)</li>
<li>Develop backend in Golang</li>
<li>Frontend with React</li>
<li>Terminal addicted with zsh and prezto framework</li>
<li>Not another git newbie</li>
<li><p>Docker centric workflow</p>

<p>  <img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2015-11-05-vim.png">
  <img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2015-11-05-zsh.png">
  <img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2015-11-05-vim-go.png"></p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dwarves Foundation]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/dwarves-foundation/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-29T00:53:06+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/dwarves-foundation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After an interesting journey at <a href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/cau-chuyen-khoi-nghiep-tu-lifebox-den-cloudjay-p1/">CloudJay</a>, I took a short break for a month and feel that startup life is too hard for young people but it&rsquo;s really worth to be a part startup scene. Someone said, one year to live in a startup is better than five years working in the enterprise. And I think this is correct. I need to face more problems and be able to solve them myself to be more mature.</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2015-06-17-entrepreneur.jpg"></p>

<p>I also find that Google Golang is interesting and it might be useful for us later. I bet my investment on it and found <a href="https://golang.org.vn">Golang Vietnam</a>, a network of Golang Developers in Vietnam.</p>

<p>Based on some connections with friends in Singapore, I start asking people about other software businesses. And begin to find my first early member. I named a team <a href="https://dwarves.foundation">Dwarves Foundation</a>. Dwarf is the small and misshapen creatures in Norse Mythology that are wisdom, natural good at smithing, mining, and crafting. My plan is to provide Tech Partner service to ventures and startups.</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2015-06-17-dwarves.jpg"></p>

<h2>Our values</h2>

<p>We are a team of geeks, hustles and startup veterans. We live around the world but most of us based in Saigon, Vietnam. We are (forever) young and always eager to learn. We have passion and experience in making cool products, esp. cloud and mobile apps. We want to help entrepreneurs solve real problems using our approachs and solutions.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Customer first</strong>: We provide the service with high quality and no latency response time. Customers have to be happy.</li>
<li><strong>Geeky style</strong>: We can do anything, wear multiple hats, take multiple approachs from official to tricky way to achieve the goal.</li>
<li><strong>Teamwork</strong>: <strong><em>Synchronisation</em></strong> and <strong><em>Collaboration</em></strong> are the most important key things. You can read this topic: <a href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/it-is-hard-to-become-a-team-member/">It&rsquo;s hard to become a team member</a>. We apply agile process to keep our spirits stick together.</li>
<li><strong>Proactive</strong>: Pick your most productivity time to work. You need to figure out yourself what you want to do and what you want to contribute aligned to the team goal as a dwarf in the tribe. We are too busy to tell you.</li>
<li><strong>Growth and sharing</strong>: You can learn another skill from other teammates. We are happy to share it to you. And we believe that working hard and improving yourself everyday will make you paid back later. Read <a href="https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-motivate-myself-to-work-hard">this topic</a> to keep yourself motivated.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Our services</h2>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Startup Factory</strong>: Our woodland is the trustworthy place where lots of ideas are validated, incubated, developed, iterated until product-market fit simultaneously and for successful ones, we turn them into new businesses. The formula repeats on its own. Moreover, we also provide startups with hands-on mentorship and seed investment programs, usually in exchange for equity.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Development Lab</strong>: Our woodland is the trustworthy place where founders could come and acquire expertise for their business models. We offer a technical partnership that takes over their whole systems and applications from development, operation to maintenance stages. We are backed by a talented, ambitious and technology-heavy workforce with years of experience. Consequently, we guarantee world-class quality for delivered products across all platforms (Web, iOS, Android).</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Talent pool</strong>: Our woodland is the trustworthy bridge for the founders who are outsourcing products to connect with talented developers in Vietnam. We guarantee the most competitive prices among competitors in local market. It is the outcome of continuously building a wide network of trust between founders and talents. The price is worth it!</p></li>
</ul>


<script async="true" class="speakerdeck-embed" data-ratio="1.77777777777778" data-id="1f4ffd51e8b049e6bce5dbdefad3786e" src="https://speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js"> </script>


<h2>Workflow at Dwarves Foundation</h2>

<h3>For project management</h3>

<p>We use Trello with Kanban theory to organize tasks. Tasks will be flew from left list to right list. We also organize lists into Scrum steps. So this will be liked:</p>

<ul>
<li>Sprint Planning</li>
<li>Current Sprint</li>
<li>In Progress</li>
<li>Blocked</li>
<li>Testing</li>
<li>Bugs Report</li>
<li>Approved</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2015-06-17-trello.png"></p>

<p>For each project, we will have <em>Sprint planning meeting</em> for Project Manager to explain project details to project members. User stories will be converted into cards or tickets and added to Trello list > <strong>Sprint Planning</strong>.</p>

<p>Usually, one sprint is about 1 or 2 weeks, we have weekly meeting to break user stories into tasks and add them to list Current Sprint. It&rsquo;s also our target for this week, we have to get in done. This time, cards need to have requirement and non requirement specification. And sometimes, if this task has some special requirement that developers need to care about, the Project Manager need to add <strong>Acceptance Criteria</strong>.</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2015-06-17-criteria.png"></p>

<p>As a customer, you are granted permission to access Trello Board to give feedback or be a tester. And most of my customers are happy with it.</p>

<p>The template for this workflow can be found at <a href="https://trello.com/b/WYgcFBgl/sprint-template">https://trello.com/b/WYgcFBgl/sprint-template</a></p>

<h3>For source code management</h3>

<p>We use <code>git</code> and GitLab. It&rsquo;s more like GitHub but for enterprise. You can have one by downloading and deploying it yourself.</p>

<p>We apply <a href="http://danielkummer.github.io/git-flow-cheatsheet/">Gitflow</a> and <code>Merge Request</code> (some people may call it Pull Request) between developers to gain some benefits from it:</p>

<ul>
<li>Can deliver anytime because branch <code>master</code> is always stable.</li>
<li>Quality source code: always review it after it&rsquo;s merged into branch <code>develep</code></li>
<li>High efficiency collaboration between team members.</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2015-06-17-gitflow.png"></p>

<p>There&rsquo;s another article about it on Atlassian site: <a href="https://www.atlassian.com/git/tutorials/comparing-workflows/feature-branch-workflow">https://www.atlassian.com/git/tutorials/comparing-workflows/feature-branch-workflow</a></p>

<p>Project Manager will be the one that init the repository on Git with some imporatant informations. For every ticket on Trello, developers need to create one issue in GitLab, create new feature branch and start the implementation on it. The <code>git commit</code> command must attach with one or more than one issue.</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2015-06-17-commit.png"></p>

<p>After that, one merge request will be created and the person who has responsibility to review this request need to check over the source code then <code>Accept</code> or <code>Reject</code> the <code>Merge Request</code>.</p>

<p>This card will be moved to list <code>Testing</code>, QC will be assigned to test this feature and so on.</p>

<h3>For Communication</h3>

<p>We use <a href="http://slack.com">Slack</a> as the main hub for all informations, from team meeting, hangout, manage tasks and source code &hellip;</p>

<p><img src="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/images/blog/2015-06-17-slack.png"></p>

<p>Slack support lots of methods to add integration. So the powerful it can be depends on what you integrate into it.</p>

<p>Finally, at the end of the day, we do daily meeting via hangout or face to face at the office to summary what we have done today and what we plan to do tomorrow. The project manager will be the one to write it down and make weekly report to customer.</p>

<p>All the processes out there are just to make the team stick together and development plan works. All team members need to understand their roles, team vision and know how to make things go on the right tracks.</p>

<p>Read more about <a href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/2014/12/05/it-is-hard-to-become-a-team-member/">Teamwork</a>.</p>

<ul>
<li>About us: <a href="http://www.dwarvesf.com">http://www.dwarvesf.com</a></li>
<li>Github: <a href="https://github.com/dwarvesf">https://github.com/dwarvesf</a></li>
<li>Hiring: <a href="https://github.com/dwarvesf/WeAreHiring">https://github.com/dwarvesf/WeAreHiring</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
