<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 9owl | Han Ngo]]></title>
  <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/blog/categories/9owl/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/"/>
  <updated>2020-06-02T02:12:00+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Han Ngo]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[nntruonghan@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[9owl - Working space that only available at night]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/9owl/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-30T16:20:21+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/9owl</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3></h3>

<p>We are members of Dwarves Foundation. We are small group of engineers and talented people. At this time we are tech partners with PearComms and Sales In One, 2 companies from Singapore. We work at the office in District 3 that we hire from a friend of the founder, it make us free to access 24/7. The office is just about 30 square meters and available for 8 to 10 9owl at the same time.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2015-05-30-team.jpg"></p>

<p>We love to work at night, not daytime. We have coffee and tea, people to talk with, place to work and corner to take a nap. We love to discuss about engineering, technology and life hacking stuffs. We are outliers, we are special and we know it. We want to make friend with people that like us.</p>

<h3>9owl &ndash; Working space that only available at night</h3>

<p>Me, have an idea that cool people should know each other, have a place to come and work at night, to be friends or not. But I believe, people that live the same lifestyle, have same mindset should be easy to make friend and more. So I start 9owl and give the office for free.</p>

<p><a href="http://dwarvesf.com/9owl/"><strong>9owl</strong></a> is <strong>invite only</strong> group and it costs you nothing. Join us for the midnight coffee, good talks, warm bed and cool work place.</p>

<p>Updated: We moved to new office on 2017 Sept and it&rsquo;s too dam cool. I&rsquo;m very happy to have you guys here.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
