<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: app | Han Ngo]]></title>
  <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/blog/categories/app/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/"/>
  <updated>2020-06-02T02:12:00+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Han Ngo]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[nntruonghan@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to use JayPix beta]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/how-to-use-jaypix-beta/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-19T05:18:50+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/how-to-use-jaypix-beta</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you are reading this post, your team registered for trial of JayPix, a visual log book for field works. You should have been received an Email from us which contains the following information and have installed successfully JayPix beta.</p>

<ul>
<li>Account Information for Login into JayPix system.</li>
<li>A AirOnApp Link for Installing the iOS JayPix app. E.g.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Now How to use JayPix beta</h2>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Step 1: You need to Login by using account information in the email you&rsquo;ve received from us</h3>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2013-10-19-iOS-UseGuide-1.png"></p>

<h3>Step 2: After logged in, you will see the Newsfeed Screen which will contain all the item in your Visual log book</h3>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2013-10-19-iOS-UseGuide-2.png"></p>

<p>But it&rsquo;s still empty, let&rsquo;s start by press the Camera button</p>

<h3>Step 3: Take a photo</h3>

<p>This is the Camera Screen where you can take a picture or load the picture in your Camera Roll by tapping on the picture icon</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2013-10-19-iOS-UseGuide-3.png"></p>

<p>After take a picture or load it from Camera roll, you can start tagging the picture by long pressing on an important part of the photo you want to be noted</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2013-10-19-iOS-UseGuide-4.png"></p>

<p>You can choose the Color for the note and type more detailed information</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2013-10-19-iOS-UseGuide-5.png"></p>

<h3>Step 4: After tapping Done, it will ask you the tittle of the photo and review the name of each note.</h3>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2013-10-19-iOS-UseGuide-6.png"></p>

<p>Then hit the check button, Jayyy, all your team will receive notification right away and know what the situation at your location immediately .</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2013-10-19-iOS-UseGuide-7.png">.</p>

<h3>Step 5: You can view other picture reported by team by tapping on the picture.</h3>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2013-10-19-iOS-UseGuide-8.png">.</p>

<p>Tap on each note to see its description</p>

<p>Tap on the More action button ( the 3-dots icon ) to save the picture for later report or call them immediately</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2013-10-19-iOS-UseGuide-9.png">.</p>

<p>One last thing: the side menu</p>

<p>On the Newsfeed sceen you can slide to the right or hit the button on the top left to view the side menu</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2013-10-19-iOS-UseGuide-10.png">.</p>

<p>You can check to view the item of every single member or sign out your account here</p>

<p>Congratulation, Now let&rsquo;s start new Journey with your team at JayPix</p>

<p>If you have any questions, please do not hesitate to contact us at <a href="&#x6d;&#x61;&#105;&#108;&#x74;&#x6f;&#58;&#x63;&#111;&#110;&#116;&#x61;&#x63;&#116;&#64;&#x63;&#x6c;&#111;&#117;&#100;&#106;&#x61;&#x79;&#x2e;&#99;&#x6f;&#109;">&#99;&#111;&#x6e;&#116;&#x61;&#99;&#116;&#64;&#99;&#108;&#111;&#x75;&#100;&#106;&#x61;&#x79;&#x2e;&#x63;&#x6f;&#109;</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
