<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: training | Han Ngo]]></title>
  <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/notes/blog/categories/training/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/notes/"/>
  <updated>2020-06-02T01:54:41+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://tieubao.github.io/notes/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Han Ngo]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[nntruonghan@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Training Android (End)]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/notes/a/training-android-end/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-02T02:04:13+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/notes/a/training-android-end</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sorry folks for that long time. I’m too busy to release CJayNet v1 and upgrade it to new version v2 so that the daily schedule of Training Android progress cannot be released fully and on time. I will summary it in this blog post.</p>

<p>After someday playing with OOP, I gave Thai a small test that build a mini chess game on console with all current knowledge about OOP. He finished in 2 weeks as expected, simple enough but the code style and architecture was too bad (also as expected).</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2014-12-02-git.png"></p>

<p>To make them can work together later, I introduced to them a concept of version control system, Git (not SVN) and Github with some basic moves that they can understand easily and can apply directly. I found some useful resources:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://rogerdudler.github.io/git-guide/">Git &ndash; The simple Guide</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://gist.github.com/jbenet/ee6c9ac48068889b0912">a simple git branching model</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://gitbookio.gitbooks.io/progit/">Gitbook</a></p></li>
</ul>


<p>Then, we started a android basic training with the material from a <a href="http://duythanhcse.wordpress.com/2013/03/19/bai-t%E1%BA%ADp-1-lam-quen-v%E1%BB%9Bi-moi-tr%C6%B0%E1%BB%9Dng-phat-tri%E1%BB%83n-di%E1%BB%87n-tho%E1%BA%A1i-di-d%E1%BB%99ng/">blog of mr Duy Thanh</a>.  This guide went through all of basic controls, how to setup environment, what we could do with android, UI design and layout  … You can also find useful resources for android developer in my previous <a href="http://tieubao.me/writing/2013/12/05/resources-every-android-developer-should-know/">blog post</a>. All the exercises source code might be found on their Github. This took them 2 months to complete all the basic lessons.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2014-12-02-trello.png"></p>

<p>June came and I began to give them more advanced lessons likes Android Concurrency, Intent Service, Broadcast Receiver, responsive UI, Database, Notification, EventBus and so on … This took more time when things became complicated. We cost almost 2 months to study all of above topics. The training course finished at the end of August with an simple app called <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.cloudjay.gossip">Gossip</a>, a clone of Secret.ly.</p>

<p>After all, I realize that, learning speed can be improved a lots if we have:</p>

<ul>
<li>Proper syllabus</li>
<li>Useful resources with visual sample</li>
<li>A diligent mentor</li>
<li>and also a working hard with high spirit student</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Training Android: Day 03 and 04]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/notes/a/training-android-day03-04/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-16T18:18:11+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/notes/a/training-android-day03-04</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thai studied faster than my expectation. At 3rd and 4th day, I give him some oop presentations from <code>mr. nmhuy</code> about <code>polymorphism</code> and <code>inheritance</code>.</p>

<p>Every time he got problem or something went wrong, we work remotely through TeamViewer and Skype. Exercises was assigned through Trello cards.</p>

<h5>Agenda</h5>

<ul>
<li>polymorphism in oop</li>
<li>inheritance in oop</li>
<li>exercises about them</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Training Android: Day 02]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/notes/a/training-android-day-02/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-13T23:22:37+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/notes/a/training-android-day-02</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thai is the only come to us on 2nd day. Because of his windows lappy cannot run Visual C or CodeBlock, I decide to teach him linux and git before continuing on OOP. Hope he will become IT geek in someday.</p>

<h5>Agenda:</h5>

<ul>
<li>Install Lubuntu</li>
<li>Setup Trello</li>
<li>Basic Linux command and practice</li>
<li>Try to run sample code on CodeBlock on Linux environment</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Training Android: Day 01]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/notes/a/training-android-day-01/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-10T23:15:40+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/notes/a/training-android-day-01</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, two friends of mine join our company training program. This course is all about Android.</p>

<p>Nam is senior student and studying Software Engineering major at HCM University of Science. The problem is with another guy, Thai. He is a graduated from Physics major with a little experience in Matlab.</p>

<p>Today is just a first day. I still have a long journey with those guy. Good luck to me.</p>

<h5>Agenda:</h5>

<ul>
<li>Eclipse and GenyMotion</li>
<li>HelloWorld app</li>
<li>Android project overview</li>
<li>Sample app: Fill in a textbox and alert the content</li>
</ul>


<p>For Thai:</p>

<ul>
<li>C basic</li>
<li>Tools and how to debug</li>
<li>OOP concept</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
