<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: startup | Han Ngo]]></title>
  <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/blog/categories/startup/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/"/>
  <updated>2020-06-02T02:12:00+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Han Ngo]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[nntruonghan@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cofounder Agreement]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/cofounder-agreement/"/>
    <updated>2018-02-15T17:41:37+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/cofounder-agreement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Ensure Alignment of Vision</h1>

<p>As you and your cofounder (or cofounders) embark on your entrepreneurial journey together, it’s imperative that you all share the same vision for the purpose and future of your company. It’s easy to get caught up in the thrill of launching a potentially successful startup together, but you all must take the time to establish the existential foundations of the company, and as early as possible, to help prevent the possibility of a drastic falling out later on.</p>

<h3>What Are Your Goals?</h3>

<ul>
<li>Why are you creating this startup?</li>
<li>What need will it fill?</li>
<li>What will your initial product/service offering be?</li>
<li>And what is your strategy for growing the company?</li>
</ul>


<h3>What Are Your Company Values and Philosophy?</h3>

<p>Your company’s success depends on vision alignment (alignment between you and your investors, your employees, and your customers, etc.). Do you share the same priorities? Do you agree on what’s most important to you both personally and for the future of your company?</p>

<h3>How Do You Measure Success?</h3>

<ul>
<li>What do you and your co-founder(s) hope to get out of this business?</li>
<li>How will you know if you’ve achieved your goals?</li>
<li>If you don’t agree on the same goals, how will you know when you’ve achieved them?</li>
</ul>


<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Discussing these issues with your co-founder could get uncomfortable, create rifts, or even uncover deal-breakers. If you are able to successfully have these difficult conversations, this is a testament to your partnership and to the strength of your relationship &mdash; and will serve as a solid foundation from which to grow your business.&rdquo; &ndash; David Ehrenberg</p></blockquote>

<h3>Working Styles and Culture</h3>

<p>Once you and your cofounder have laid down the aspirational and philosophical groundwork for your startup, this is also the ideal time to determine what kind of working environment best complements the vision of your startup.</p>

<ul>
<li>What 3 words best describe the startup culture you want to create (e.g. open, hard-working, eccentric, etc.)? Pro-tip: If you’re really serious and far along go visit few office spaces together to get a sense of what each of you likes work environments wise and why.</li>
<li>What values do we want to instill in our employees?</li>
<li>If you could pick 2 things to change about our company, and two things to bring with you from your previous experience, what would they be and why?</li>
<li>How much equity are we allocating for future employees?</li>
<li>What should we look for in our first 5 hires?</li>
<li>Describe your ideal working style.</li>
</ul>


<h1>Legal Decisions &amp; Definitions</h1>

<h3>General Questions</h3>

<ul>
<li>Is the percentage ownership subject to vesting based on continued participation in the business?</li>
<li>If one founder leaves, does the company or the other founder have the right to buy back that founder’s shares? At what price?=</li>
<li>What salaries (if any), are the founders entitled to? How can that be changed?</li>
<li>How are key decisions and day-to-day decisions of the business to be made?</li>
</ul>


<h3>Basic Legal Definitions</h3>

<p>Harroch&rsquo;s article also explores numerous basic legal terms associated with launching a startup, all of which you and your business partner should familiarize yourselves with.</p>

<ul>
<li>Confidentiality Agreements &ndash; These are also referred to as Non-Disclosure Agreements or NDAs. The purpose of the agreement is to allow the holder of confidential information to share it with a third party.</li>
<li>Copyright &ndash; A copyright gives the owner the exclusive right to make copies of the work and to prepare derivative works (such as sequels or revisions) based on the work.</li>
<li>General Partnership &ndash; If there is more than one founder, a general partnership is often chosen as the legal form of business entity.</li>
<li>Patent &ndash; A patent gives its inventor the right to prevent others from making, using, or selling the patented subjected matter described in words in the patent’s claims.</li>
<li>Service marks &ndash; Service marks resemble trademarks and are used to identify services.</li>
<li>Tax Incentive &ndash; Depending on the nature of the business, various tax incentives may be available, such as renewable energy tax credits and investment tax credits.</li>
<li>Trademark &ndash; A trademark right protects the symbolic value of a word, name, symbol, or device that the trademark owner used to identify or distinguish its good from those of others.</li>
<li>Trade Secret &ndash; A trade secret right allows the owner of the right to take action against anyone who breaches an agreement or confidential relationship or who steals or uses other improper means to obtain secret information.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Include a Vesting Schedule When Issuing Shares to Co-founders</h3>

<p>When you create a vesting schedule, this means that the co-founder will earn their shares over time and protects you and the company if that a co-founder leaves the company or doesn&rsquo;t pull their weight. The standard vesting period is four years, with monthly vesting of shares. Unvested shares should be subject to repurchase by the company if the co-founder leaves the company.</p>

<h3>Protect Your Valuable Intellectual Property</h3>

<p>If intellectual property is a vital element of your business, it&rsquo;s important to protect that IP during the formative stages of a company. You can address this issue by relying on patents, trademarks, copyrights, and trade secrets to protect your valuable IP. Another step you can take is requiring all co-founders and any third-party developers to assign to the company their rights in IP they created and that is utilized by the company. Doing this will help prevent trouble if a co-founder leaves the company and takes a crucial patent with them.</p>

<h1>How to Split Equity</h1>

<h3>Ideas are Valuable</h3>

<p>If you brought the original concept to the table, increase your share holdings by about 5 percent. While execution is more important in the long run, whoever conceived the original idea deserves a little extra credit.</p>

<h3>That First Step is a Doozy</h3>

<p>Bringing something of value to the company during its formative stages – like a filed patent (not a provisional), a compelling demo, an early version of the product, or something else that means much of the work towards financing or revenue is already done – you should receive a considerable part of the equity.</p>

<h3>Full Time Commitment is Expensive</h3>

<p>Bottom line, if you’re working more, then you’re risking a lot more if the project fails, which means that you are entitled to more if the project succeeds. Also, keep in mind that part-time cofounders are a big minus to someone considering an investment, so choose your partners wisely.</p>

<h3>The CEO Gets More. Always.</h3>

<p>Splitting equity equally means that no one controls the company more than anyone else. But if that’s the case, than having a CEO is useless, as well as having any form of upper management. So, whoever is the designated CEO should get another slightly more equity. If you think that’s unfair, remember that market rate for a great CEO is higher than market rate for a great CTO, which means that’s how it is everywhere.</p>

<h3>Reputation Counts</h3>

<p>If you’re a beginning entrepreneur and your partner is an experienced founder with an established reputation, they deserve more equity. If that founder has an expansive network that benefits the company, they deserve more equity. If that founder can help secure more funding for your company, they deserve more equity.</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;The question of equity brings out the most fundamental differences, perceptions, and values in an aspiring startup. In fact the equity question, more than any other, may strangle a young company before it can even get started. And that’s a damn good thing.&rdquo; &ndash; Dan Shapiro</p></blockquote>

<h1>Final Thoughts</h1>

<p>Yes, talking about such topics as company roles and vision and equity and the like can be uncomfortable among founders. However, these discussions are vital to a successful partnership, as well as a successful startup, and must be held before any of you invest too much time, energy, and money into a potential company. Keep in mind that whoever you decide to launch a company with, you all will have to make countless difficult decisions once your company is actually up and running. If you take nothing else from this blog post, at least follow the bit of advice below:</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Choose co-founders the way you would choose a spouse. The reality is that you will, at least in the early days, spend far more time with your co-founders than your partner.&rdquo; &ndash; Danielle Newnham</p></blockquote>

<h4>Source: <a href="https://fi.co/insight/how-to-create-the-perfect-cofounder-agreement-with-your-business-partner">fi.co</a></h4>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[12 Signs Your Company Has An Enviable Workplace Culture]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/12-signs-your-company-has-an-enviable-workplace-culture/"/>
    <updated>2017-01-09T16:36:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/12-signs-your-company-has-an-enviable-workplace-culture</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This article is one of my favorites about company culture. At <a href="http://dwarvesf.com">Dwarves Foundation</a>, we pursue the path of high tech Ventures Builder where we can be the foundation for all tech startups for now and even for Industry 4.0. Building the culture for engineer team is the highest priority.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>Source:</strong> <a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/3040723/12-signs-your-company-has-an-enviable-workplace-culture">fastcompany</a></p>

<p>Many years ago I worked for a small organization that was effecting change on a national level. It was known for excellence, vision, and world-class leadership. It had a clear mission and strategy. With my acceptance into this organization came the respect of my friends and family for the achievement of such an honor.</p>

<p>But within a few months, I began to realize the department where I was placed did not represent the values of the overall organization. The leadership was more interested in saving face than making decisions based on integrity. Staff members talked about one another in highly negative terms. Complaining and whining were the most common modes of communication. There was little respect for the contribution of others on the team.</p>

<p>A friend and I tried to swing things back to a positive place, but we were sarcastically branded &ldquo;Danny and Darla Do-Right&rdquo; since we wouldn’t participate in the negativity. Efforts to make central leadership aware of the toxic nature of the culture were directed back to department leadership—which, of course, was where the problems began. The department completely fractured toward the end of our assignment, and most team members left the organization hurt and disillusioned. Richard Dore, the director of Proteus Leadership Centres, explains what happened this way:</p>

<blockquote><p>Having a great workplace culture can appear to be rare—and creating one is elusive and near impossible for some managers. People are often frustrated by their culture, with some describing their workplace as being dominated by negative and toxic personalities, with underhanded and manipulative infighting that stifles growth, innovation and results.</p></blockquote>

<p>There is nothing worse than working in an organization that has a bad culture. It doesn’t matter how much money you make or how many weeks of vacation you are given; when you work in a toxic environment, you still come home tense and stressed at the end of each day. And that isn’t worth it.</p>

<p>On the other hand, there is nothing better than working at an organization with a great culture. You wake up every day looking forward to getting back to work on the mission with people you enjoy being around.</p>

<p>I’m sure this list isn’t exhaustive, but here are twelve signs that a great culture exists in your organization or company:</p>

<h3>1. PEOPLE ARE WAITING IN LINE TO JOIN YOUR TEAM</h3>

<p>It’s not because you are offering more money than they could find somewhere else. Many times the pay is less. But people have heard about your team, and they would give anything to be a part of it.</p>

<h3>2. TURNOVER IS LOW</h3>

<p>You should especially pay attention to this in entry-level and mid-level jobs. Often top leaders will stay forever because it’s safe and the pay is good. But if you see people staying for an unexpectedly long time in facility care or accounting, you are probably looking at a healthy culture.</p>

<h3>3. TOP LEADERS ARE NOT INSECURE ABOUT OTHER LEADERS SUCCEEDING</h3>

<p>In fact, they encourage it.</p>

<h3>4. GOSSIP ISN’T TOLERATED</h3>

<p>It isn’t just the leaders calling for people to take the high road in their communication. At every level, gossip is shut down with an encouragement to speak directly to the individual.</p>

<h3>5. LATERAL LEADERSHIP IS OUTSTANDING</h3>

<p>Leading people below you is easy. That is, it’s easy compared to leading people next to you over whom you have no authority. A great culture sees people coming alongside their peers to encourage, or occasionally to correct and redirect.</p>

<h3>6. TEAM MEMBERS ARE ENERGIZED BY THE MISSION</h3>

<p>You hear leaders at all levels of the organization talking about the mission. It gives them energy, and they are constantly thinking of ways to get it done.</p>

<h3>7. IT’S NOT JUST A JOB</h3>

<p>People go to movies, hang out at one another’s homes, and sometimes even vacation together. This doesn’t mean they don’t have other friends, but they really enjoy the company of the people they work with.</p>

<h3>8. THE TEAM BELIEVES THEY ARE MORE IMPORTANT THAN THE TASK</h3>

<p>There is a sense that, as employees, they really matter. They aren’t just people filling tasks; but the culture, systems, language, and structure communicate value. Even in tough times with salary freezes or benefit changes, the vibe is still, &ldquo;You matter!&rdquo;</p>

<h3>9. PEOPLE ARE SMILING</h3>

<p>Walk the hallways and you will see people smiling, enjoying conversations, and having a good time in the midst of high productivity and intense focus.</p>

<h3>10. FEAR IS MISSING</h3>

<p>People don’t fret if they say the wrong thing in front of the wrong person. There aren’t hushed conversations because of the fear of what will happen if they are overheard. Employees in an organization with a great culture can walk into the boss’s office with a concern and walk out knowing they were heard.</p>

<h3>11. COMMUNICATION IS STRONG</h3>

<p>From the top to the bottom, people communicate. The staff isn’t surprised with information they didn’t hear until it was announced at a Sunday service or came out in a new product brochure. It is communicated well in advance, with leaders even asking the staff to help find solutions.</p>

<h3>12. CHANGE IS WELCOME</h3>

<p>People aren’t afraid of change. It’s not that everyone likes change, but most have been through it so many times and have seen the leaders manage change with care and dignity that they no longer dread it. Identifying the evidences of a great culture is all fine and good.</p>

<p>This list might be discouraging if you aren’t working in an environment with such a healthy culture. To that person I would suggest: You have the power to change the culture, one day at a time! Building a healthy culture starts with a few determined people.</p>

<p>In just one department, in one corner of the building, a new culture can begin to emerge. As others interact with the healthy department, they are attracted to it. At their core, no one wants to live in a culture of negativity. People want to love their job. They might not know how to act in a positive environment, and they might resist as you call them out of a place of mediocrity, but ultimately love and positivity always wins out.</p>

<p>Get with others who have the same desire, and take that first step!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The CEO roles: Idea to Continuous Growth]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/the-ceo-roles-idea-to-continuous-growth/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-17T12:37:33+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/the-ceo-roles-idea-to-continuous-growth</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A CEO role must evolve to sustain growth. Where are you in the growth journey?</p>

<h1>Start Up</h1>

<p>Here CEOs are:</p>

<ul>
<li>Doers, the &lsquo;Jacks and Janes&rsquo; of all trades.</li>
<li>Decision makers</li>
</ul>


<h1>Initial Growth</h1>

<p>CEOs must:</p>

<ul>
<li>Learn to delegate</li>
<li>Learn how to attract and recruit the right people</li>
<li>Set the company direction</li>
</ul>


<h1>Rapid Growth</h1>

<p>CEOs need to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Hire people with more knowledge than themselves in the key business functions</li>
<li>Get the team to function as a &lsquo;team&rsquo;, to plan and communicate</li>
</ul>


<h1>Continuous Growth</h1>

<p>CEOs need to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Become strategic innovators &amp; change catalysts</li>
<li>Lead the company culture</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="/images/blog/2016-09-17-ceo-roles.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy Startup]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/happy-startup/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-10T09:59:05+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/happy-startup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Follow these 10 tips and you’ll be on the right track to a happy startup:</p>

<ul>
<li>Define your startup DNA</li>
<li>Keep the main thing, the main thing</li>
<li>Bring design on board from day one</li>
<li>Validate ideas early and test assumptions</li>
<li>Build a business, not a pitch</li>
<li>Stop selling and start listening</li>
<li>Get the balance right between MVP and perfection</li>
<li>Get a mentor and build your support network</li>
<li>90% of entrepreneurship is sales. It’s time to start hustling.</li>
<li>It’s all about people. Hire the best you can</li>
</ul>


<p>Full article at
<a href="https://medium.com/the-happy-startup-school/10-ways-youll-probably-f-k-up-your-startup-25b830afbd84">Medium</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How do we split equity between co-founders?]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/how-do-we-split-equity-between-us-co-founders/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-09T17:06:03+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/how-do-we-split-equity-between-us-co-founders</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s a very fair question to ask. My own co-founder Bryan and I asked the same question of ourselves when we launched our startup Embarke. Bryan and I had only known each other for a couple months, yet it was important to both of us to have an open and honest partnership from day one. We also knew the importance of figuring this stuff out early, while we could still look at it objectively.</p>

<p>The purpose of this post is to not just share with you what we did and the process we went through, but to also give you the tool we built to help us along the way.</p>

<h2>Yes, it can be uncomfortable. Get over it.</h2>

<p>I’ve seen far too many founders put this off because it’s an uncomfortable conversation. The reality is, if you’re not comfortable talking about uncomfortable things with your co-founder(s) &hellip; you’ve got bigger problems. This relationship can’t be one of secrecy or procrastination. The nature of an entrepreneur is to take something on…head on…and right now. This equity split conversation is one of the first (of very many more) uncomfortable conversations that you’ll have with your co-founder, and it’s a great signal for how well you’ll work through future situations.</p>

<blockquote><p>This relationship can’t be one of secrecy or procrastination. The nature of an entrepreneur is to take something on&mdash;head on&mdash;and right now.</p></blockquote>

<p>So, we started digging and found countless resources talking about how equity should and shouldn’t be split among founders. The problem (with any advice) is, everyone’s got an opinion. Many of those opinions of course are based on their previous experience which may or may not be related to your situation, how far along the business is, and countless other variables. So, with all of these opinions and calculators out there, how did we come to terms with it?</p>

<p>We used them all.</p>

<p>Then we built our own tool to leverage them, and dove in.</p>

<h2>It’s not about you.</h2>

<p>It’s important to realize that this isn’t entirely about you. Through this process, we learned things about each other we didn’t know. We learned more about each other’s skill sets, our pasts, projects, accomplishments, and what we could each truly bring to the table. Sure, it’s a little about you. But it’s got to be about your co-founder(s) as well&hellip; so you need to have an open and receptive mind.</p>

<p>What was the end result for us? We were both very happy with the outcome, we learned a TON about each other that we didn’t know before, and walked away from the process more comfortable about working together than ever.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Alright already. Give me the tool!&rdquo;</p>

<p>Bryan and I each took our tool and started mapping out what aspects we felt were important to our business, and what we felt we each brought to the table. We did this independently of each other over a day or two. Then, we sat down and went through everything item-by-item. That is where the magic happens.</p>

<p><a href="https://al.bsharah.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/Embarke-CoFounder-Equity-Split-Template-2016-01.xlsx">The spreadsheet</a> has 5 different calculators in it, and a final box that averages everything out among all 5. Hopefully it’s intuitive enough for you to use. Any questions, hit me up in the comments!</p>

<h4>Source: <a href="https://al.bsharah.com/co-founders-its-time-to-split-that-equity/">AL BSHARAH</a></h4>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
