<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: startup | Han Ngo]]></title>
  <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/blog/categories/startup/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/"/>
  <updated>2020-06-02T02:20:45+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Han Ngo]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[nntruonghan@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cofounder Agreement]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/cofounder-agreement/"/>
    <updated>2018-02-15T17:41:37+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/cofounder-agreement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1>Ensure Alignment of Vision</h1>

<p>As you and your cofounder (or cofounders) embark on your entrepreneurial journey together, it’s imperative that you all share the same vision for the purpose and future of your company. It’s easy to get caught up in the thrill of launching a potentially successful startup together, but you all must take the time to establish the existential foundations of the company, and as early as possible, to help prevent the possibility of a drastic falling out later on.</p>

<h3>What Are Your Goals?</h3>

<ul>
<li>Why are you creating this startup?</li>
<li>What need will it fill?</li>
<li>What will your initial product/service offering be?</li>
<li>And what is your strategy for growing the company?</li>
</ul>


<h3>What Are Your Company Values and Philosophy?</h3>

<p>Your company’s success depends on vision alignment (alignment between you and your investors, your employees, and your customers, etc.). Do you share the same priorities? Do you agree on what’s most important to you both personally and for the future of your company?</p>

<h3>How Do You Measure Success?</h3>

<ul>
<li>What do you and your co-founder(s) hope to get out of this business?</li>
<li>How will you know if you’ve achieved your goals?</li>
<li>If you don’t agree on the same goals, how will you know when you’ve achieved them?</li>
</ul>


<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Discussing these issues with your co-founder could get uncomfortable, create rifts, or even uncover deal-breakers. If you are able to successfully have these difficult conversations, this is a testament to your partnership and to the strength of your relationship &mdash; and will serve as a solid foundation from which to grow your business.&rdquo; &ndash; David Ehrenberg</p></blockquote>

<h3>Working Styles and Culture</h3>

<p>Once you and your cofounder have laid down the aspirational and philosophical groundwork for your startup, this is also the ideal time to determine what kind of working environment best complements the vision of your startup.</p>

<ul>
<li>What 3 words best describe the startup culture you want to create (e.g. open, hard-working, eccentric, etc.)? Pro-tip: If you’re really serious and far along go visit few office spaces together to get a sense of what each of you likes work environments wise and why.</li>
<li>What values do we want to instill in our employees?</li>
<li>If you could pick 2 things to change about our company, and two things to bring with you from your previous experience, what would they be and why?</li>
<li>How much equity are we allocating for future employees?</li>
<li>What should we look for in our first 5 hires?</li>
<li>Describe your ideal working style.</li>
</ul>


<h1>Legal Decisions &amp; Definitions</h1>

<h3>General Questions</h3>

<ul>
<li>Is the percentage ownership subject to vesting based on continued participation in the business?</li>
<li>If one founder leaves, does the company or the other founder have the right to buy back that founder’s shares? At what price?=</li>
<li>What salaries (if any), are the founders entitled to? How can that be changed?</li>
<li>How are key decisions and day-to-day decisions of the business to be made?</li>
</ul>


<h3>Basic Legal Definitions</h3>

<p>Harroch&rsquo;s article also explores numerous basic legal terms associated with launching a startup, all of which you and your business partner should familiarize yourselves with.</p>

<ul>
<li>Confidentiality Agreements &ndash; These are also referred to as Non-Disclosure Agreements or NDAs. The purpose of the agreement is to allow the holder of confidential information to share it with a third party.</li>
<li>Copyright &ndash; A copyright gives the owner the exclusive right to make copies of the work and to prepare derivative works (such as sequels or revisions) based on the work.</li>
<li>General Partnership &ndash; If there is more than one founder, a general partnership is often chosen as the legal form of business entity.</li>
<li>Patent &ndash; A patent gives its inventor the right to prevent others from making, using, or selling the patented subjected matter described in words in the patent’s claims.</li>
<li>Service marks &ndash; Service marks resemble trademarks and are used to identify services.</li>
<li>Tax Incentive &ndash; Depending on the nature of the business, various tax incentives may be available, such as renewable energy tax credits and investment tax credits.</li>
<li>Trademark &ndash; A trademark right protects the symbolic value of a word, name, symbol, or device that the trademark owner used to identify or distinguish its good from those of others.</li>
<li>Trade Secret &ndash; A trade secret right allows the owner of the right to take action against anyone who breaches an agreement or confidential relationship or who steals or uses other improper means to obtain secret information.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Include a Vesting Schedule When Issuing Shares to Co-founders</h3>

<p>When you create a vesting schedule, this means that the co-founder will earn their shares over time and protects you and the company if that a co-founder leaves the company or doesn&rsquo;t pull their weight. The standard vesting period is four years, with monthly vesting of shares. Unvested shares should be subject to repurchase by the company if the co-founder leaves the company.</p>

<h3>Protect Your Valuable Intellectual Property</h3>

<p>If intellectual property is a vital element of your business, it&rsquo;s important to protect that IP during the formative stages of a company. You can address this issue by relying on patents, trademarks, copyrights, and trade secrets to protect your valuable IP. Another step you can take is requiring all co-founders and any third-party developers to assign to the company their rights in IP they created and that is utilized by the company. Doing this will help prevent trouble if a co-founder leaves the company and takes a crucial patent with them.</p>

<h1>How to Split Equity</h1>

<h3>Ideas are Valuable</h3>

<p>If you brought the original concept to the table, increase your share holdings by about 5 percent. While execution is more important in the long run, whoever conceived the original idea deserves a little extra credit.</p>

<h3>That First Step is a Doozy</h3>

<p>Bringing something of value to the company during its formative stages – like a filed patent (not a provisional), a compelling demo, an early version of the product, or something else that means much of the work towards financing or revenue is already done – you should receive a considerable part of the equity.</p>

<h3>Full Time Commitment is Expensive</h3>

<p>Bottom line, if you’re working more, then you’re risking a lot more if the project fails, which means that you are entitled to more if the project succeeds. Also, keep in mind that part-time cofounders are a big minus to someone considering an investment, so choose your partners wisely.</p>

<h3>The CEO Gets More. Always.</h3>

<p>Splitting equity equally means that no one controls the company more than anyone else. But if that’s the case, than having a CEO is useless, as well as having any form of upper management. So, whoever is the designated CEO should get another slightly more equity. If you think that’s unfair, remember that market rate for a great CEO is higher than market rate for a great CTO, which means that’s how it is everywhere.</p>

<h3>Reputation Counts</h3>

<p>If you’re a beginning entrepreneur and your partner is an experienced founder with an established reputation, they deserve more equity. If that founder has an expansive network that benefits the company, they deserve more equity. If that founder can help secure more funding for your company, they deserve more equity.</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;The question of equity brings out the most fundamental differences, perceptions, and values in an aspiring startup. In fact the equity question, more than any other, may strangle a young company before it can even get started. And that’s a damn good thing.&rdquo; &ndash; Dan Shapiro</p></blockquote>

<h1>Final Thoughts</h1>

<p>Yes, talking about such topics as company roles and vision and equity and the like can be uncomfortable among founders. However, these discussions are vital to a successful partnership, as well as a successful startup, and must be held before any of you invest too much time, energy, and money into a potential company. Keep in mind that whoever you decide to launch a company with, you all will have to make countless difficult decisions once your company is actually up and running. If you take nothing else from this blog post, at least follow the bit of advice below:</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;Choose co-founders the way you would choose a spouse. The reality is that you will, at least in the early days, spend far more time with your co-founders than your partner.&rdquo; &ndash; Danielle Newnham</p></blockquote>

<h4>Source: <a href="https://fi.co/insight/how-to-create-the-perfect-cofounder-agreement-with-your-business-partner">fi.co</a></h4>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The CEO roles: Idea to Continuous Growth]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/the-ceo-roles-idea-to-continuous-growth/"/>
    <updated>2016-09-17T12:37:33+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/the-ceo-roles-idea-to-continuous-growth</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A CEO role must evolve to sustain growth. Where are you in the growth journey?</p>

<h1>Start Up</h1>

<p>Here CEOs are:</p>

<ul>
<li>Doers, the &lsquo;Jacks and Janes&rsquo; of all trades.</li>
<li>Decision makers</li>
</ul>


<h1>Initial Growth</h1>

<p>CEOs must:</p>

<ul>
<li>Learn to delegate</li>
<li>Learn how to attract and recruit the right people</li>
<li>Set the company direction</li>
</ul>


<h1>Rapid Growth</h1>

<p>CEOs need to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Hire people with more knowledge than themselves in the key business functions</li>
<li>Get the team to function as a &lsquo;team&rsquo;, to plan and communicate</li>
</ul>


<h1>Continuous Growth</h1>

<p>CEOs need to:</p>

<ul>
<li>Become strategic innovators &amp; change catalysts</li>
<li>Lead the company culture</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="/images/blog/2016-09-17-ceo-roles.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How do we split equity between co-founders?]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/how-do-we-split-equity-between-us-co-founders/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-09T17:06:03+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/how-do-we-split-equity-between-us-co-founders</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It’s a very fair question to ask. My own co-founder Bryan and I asked the same question of ourselves when we launched our startup Embarke. Bryan and I had only known each other for a couple months, yet it was important to both of us to have an open and honest partnership from day one. We also knew the importance of figuring this stuff out early, while we could still look at it objectively.</p>

<p>The purpose of this post is to not just share with you what we did and the process we went through, but to also give you the tool we built to help us along the way.</p>

<h2>Yes, it can be uncomfortable. Get over it.</h2>

<p>I’ve seen far too many founders put this off because it’s an uncomfortable conversation. The reality is, if you’re not comfortable talking about uncomfortable things with your co-founder(s) &hellip; you’ve got bigger problems. This relationship can’t be one of secrecy or procrastination. The nature of an entrepreneur is to take something on…head on…and right now. This equity split conversation is one of the first (of very many more) uncomfortable conversations that you’ll have with your co-founder, and it’s a great signal for how well you’ll work through future situations.</p>

<blockquote><p>This relationship can’t be one of secrecy or procrastination. The nature of an entrepreneur is to take something on&mdash;head on&mdash;and right now.</p></blockquote>

<p>So, we started digging and found countless resources talking about how equity should and shouldn’t be split among founders. The problem (with any advice) is, everyone’s got an opinion. Many of those opinions of course are based on their previous experience which may or may not be related to your situation, how far along the business is, and countless other variables. So, with all of these opinions and calculators out there, how did we come to terms with it?</p>

<p>We used them all.</p>

<p>Then we built our own tool to leverage them, and dove in.</p>

<h2>It’s not about you.</h2>

<p>It’s important to realize that this isn’t entirely about you. Through this process, we learned things about each other we didn’t know. We learned more about each other’s skill sets, our pasts, projects, accomplishments, and what we could each truly bring to the table. Sure, it’s a little about you. But it’s got to be about your co-founder(s) as well&hellip; so you need to have an open and receptive mind.</p>

<p>What was the end result for us? We were both very happy with the outcome, we learned a TON about each other that we didn’t know before, and walked away from the process more comfortable about working together than ever.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Alright already. Give me the tool!&rdquo;</p>

<p>Bryan and I each took our tool and started mapping out what aspects we felt were important to our business, and what we felt we each brought to the table. We did this independently of each other over a day or two. Then, we sat down and went through everything item-by-item. That is where the magic happens.</p>

<p><a href="https://al.bsharah.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/Embarke-CoFounder-Equity-Split-Template-2016-01.xlsx">The spreadsheet</a> has 5 different calculators in it, and a final box that averages everything out among all 5. Hopefully it’s intuitive enough for you to use. Any questions, hit me up in the comments!</p>

<h4>Source: <a href="https://al.bsharah.com/co-founders-its-time-to-split-that-equity/">AL BSHARAH</a></h4>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Divide Founders Stock Equally? Bad Idea]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/divide-founders-stock-equally-bad-idea/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-05T16:51:32+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/divide-founders-stock-equally-bad-idea</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You and some co-venturers have come up with a business plan and an idea that you want to bring to fruition. How do you decide how much each person will own in the company?</p>

<p>Many entrepreneurs think that each founder should own equal shares. This can be problematic, for many reasons.</p>

<p>Here are a few things to think about when dividing ownership and founders stock.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Who is bringing the funds to the table?</strong> Money is important and without initial funding, you can&rsquo;t get a business off the ground. But is the bank-roller entitled to a larger proportion of the shares? The decision will depend on how much money he or she is putting in and what his or her additional roles are in the company.</li>
<li><strong>Whose idea was it?</strong> There is some value to put on the original idea. But simply coming up with the idea shouldn&rsquo;t give majority ownership to the founder. Was the idea patented? A patented idea carries more tangible weight than an abstract idea.</li>
<li><strong>Who will be doing the lion&rsquo;s share of the work?</strong> Set agreements on day one for who will be contributing work. One person may be contributing valuable managerial labor while another one might be designing important elements.</li>
<li><strong>What are your business projections?</strong> This is an important question because it helps you figure out who is in the company for the long haul. Which brings us to the final point.</li>
<li><strong>Have vesting restrictions.</strong> Your stock agreements should have provisions stating that no founder can pull out stock in the company until the lapse of a certain period of time. The last thing you want is for someone to put in the minimal and cash out early at the same proportion as the founders who are toiling away daily.</li>
</ul>


<p>Equity splitting between founders is very important and can be the source of much business litigation in the future. Remember that the startup equity sharing can also bring control issues and voting issues. You need to be careful who has control and who has voting rights in the company as well.</p>

<p>Also <strong>keep in mind that not everyone needs to be an &ldquo;owner.&rdquo;</strong> You don&rsquo;t want too many cooks in the kitchen. See if any of the initial contributors can have a different role, perhaps as a key employee with a different class of stock ownership.</p>

<h4>Source: <a href="https://blogs.findlaw.com/free_enterprise/2012/04/equal-shares-for-founders-stock-bad-idea.html">FindLaw</a></h4>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What does it feel like being the CEO of a startup?]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/cam-giac-khi-tro-thanh-ceo-cua-mot-startup/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-22T22:24:07+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/cam-giac-khi-tro-thanh-ceo-cua-mot-startup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Cảm ơn dịch giả, anh Ninh vì bài dịch này. Xin được phép trích lại bài dịch của anh để mọi người có cơ hội hiểu thêm về những cảm giác mà một đồng sáng lập / key member (không chỉ là CEO) phải trải qua khi thực sự <em>dành hết sức của mình</em> cho công việc.</p>

<h4><strong>Nguồn:</strong> <a href="http://ghichep.ninhnv.com/2012/06/cam-giac-nao-khi-tham-gia-mot-cong-ty.html">http://ghichep.ninhnv.com/</a></h4>

<p>Cảm giác thế nào khi bạn tham gia gây dựng một công ty startup? <a href="http://qr.ae/3YjjZ">Câu trả lời của Paul Dejoe trên Quora</a> với hơn 1400 votes (hiện tại là khoảng 5800 votes) đã tóm gọn gần như đầy đủ các cung bậc cảm xúc của những người làm startup.</p>

<hr />

<p>Cảm giác thế nào ư? Mỗi đêm bạn đều trằn trọc khó ngủ. Ngày cuối tuần chẳng còn nghĩa lý gì nữa. Các vòng đầu tư cũng chẳng giúp bạn nhẹ nhõm hơn được gì. Vì điều đó có nghĩa là càng có nhiều người trông cậy vào bạn mang lại lợi nhuận gấp 20 lần số tiền họ đã đầu tư vào bạn. Và thật là khó khăn để dứt bỏ các suy nghĩ về công ty. Ngay kể cả TV, phim ảnh hay các kỳ nghỉ lễ cũng trở nên nhàm chán khi mà tương lai, vận mệnh của công ty bạn đang ở đâu đó trong Inbox hay kết quả từ một bài test A/B bạn vừa quyết định chạy thử.</p>

<p>Bạn cảm thấy thật tội lỗi khi làm gì đó bạn thích ngoài công việc ra. Trải qua hàng năm trời vật lộn với cuộc chiến nội tâm, bạn mới nhận ra rằng, giữ cho cuộc sống &ldquo;cân bằng&rdquo; là cả một nghệ thuật. Nó quan trọng chẳng kém các kỹ năng bạn vốn hằng ao ước.</p>

<p>Bạn bắt đầu cảm thấy sáng tạo có giá trị dường nào và bạn buộc lòng phải suy nghĩ một cách khác biệt, không chỉ để thắng cuộc mà còn để nhìn ra cơ hội tốt nhất. Bạn nhận ra những ý tưởng tốt nhất nảy sinh không phải là khi bạn dán mắt vào màn hình. Những trò giải trí tiêu khiển nhẹ nhàng lành mạnh lại mang lại hiệu quả tức thì không ngờ đến.</p>

<p>Bạn bắt đầu thấy nể phục mấy con vịt. Quẫy đạp như điên dưới nước mà phía trên vẫn phải tìm cách nhẹ nhàng, ung dung khi mọi người ngước nhìn. Bạn thấm thía một điều rằng nếu bạn đánh mất đi cá tính, phong thái của mình, tức là bạn thua cuộc.</p>

<p>Bạn luôn luôn tự hỏi liệu mình có đang thay đổi thế giới ngày một tốt đẹp hơn? Hay người ta sống có tốt hơn từ ngày biết đến bạn không?</p>

<p>Bạn sáng tạo và khi bạn có một ý tưởng, dường như chẳng có gì có thể cản trở bạn cho đến khi bạn biến được nó thành sự thật. Bạn có cảm giác này đơn giản là vì bạn không thể làm khác đi được. Bạn bắt đầu cảm nhận cụm từ &ldquo;entrepreneur&rdquo; gần gũi hơn. Thật khó để giải thích cho bạn bè rằng không mạo hiểm như bạn chẳng qua là vì trong đầu họ chất đầy nỗi lo sợ không dám thúc đẩy bản thân hành động hay mang tất cả những gì đang có ra để chiến đấu cho dù thật bại luôn rình rập hàng ngày. Bạn bắt đầu biến các cuộc chuyện trò có liên quan thành câu chuyện làm thế nào có thể khai thác các cơ hội thành lợi ích nó mang lại. Những người gần gũi với bạn sẽ nhìn vào những gì bạn quan tâm theo một cách hoàn toàn khác bởi vì họ chẳng hiểu gì cả. Bạn không trách cứ gì họ. Họ không thể hiểu nếu họ chưa từng tự mình làm điều gì đó tương tự. Đó là lý do tại sao bạn cứ đi tìm cách thuyết phục người khác trở thành Entrepreneur như bạn. Bạn cảm thấy có được phần thưởng xứng đáng khi giúp đỡ các entrepreneurs khác. Đây là email của tôi: <a href="&#109;&#x61;&#x69;&#x6c;&#116;&#111;&#58;&#112;&#x61;&#117;&#x6c;&#x40;&#x65;&#99;&#x71;&#117;&#x69;&#x72;&#101;&#x2e;&#x63;&#111;&#x6d;&#x2e;">&#x70;&#97;&#117;&#108;&#x40;&#x65;&#x63;&#113;&#117;&#x69;&#x72;&#101;&#x2e;&#99;&#x6f;&#109;&#46;</a> Hãy cho tôi biết tôi có thể giúp gì cho bạn không.</p>

<p>Việc của bạn là tạo ra một tầm nhìn, một văn hóa, đưa đúng người lên chiếc xe cùng bạn và truyền cảm hứng cho họ. Khi bạn nhìn đồng đội của mình tin tưởng vào tầm nhìn đó, cũng nhiều chẳng kém gì bạn, và tin tưởng bạn sẽ luôn làm đúng, nó là cảm giác không thể diễn tả nổi. Nỗ lực làm việc hơn người theo cấp số mũ luôn khiến bạn ngạc nhiên. Đó là lý do tại sao tìm đúng đồng đội là điều khó khăn nhất nhưng cũng là điều quan trọng nhất. Bài học này sẽ ảnh hưởng đáng kể đến cuộc đời bạn sau này. Bạn sẽ không còn tìm cách giữ mọi thứ bình bình nữa vì bạn biết điều gì có thể xẩy ra khi bạn kiên trì mãnh liệt chiến đấu cho những gì tốt đẹp nhất và tìm thấy những cộng sự tuyệt vời. Sẽ chẳng còn là vấn đề khi thẳng thắn với mọi người mà không sợ làm tổn thương họ.</p>

<p>Bạn bắt đầu nhận ra rằng bạn là một lãnh đạo và bạn phải dẫn dắt hoặc bạn không thể theo được nữa. Bạn gạt đi những lời chào mời gạ bán vì bạn cần làm chủ cuộc chơi và bạn cảm thấy rằng các đồng đội của bạn là những người tuyệt vời nhất thế giới. Bạn có thể làm bất cứ thứ gì một cách chăm chỉ, cần mẫn. Từ bỏ không phải là một lựa chọn.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2015-01-22-ceo-startup-quote.png"></p>

<p>Bạn phải sẵn sàng ngủ lại công ty và thấy thoải mái với việc đó. Bạn có thể cười vào mọi thứ vì khi bạn nghĩ về những điều tồi tệ hơn có thể xẩy đến với công ty mình, thực tế là nó hoàn toàn có thể sẽ xảy ra. Hãy tưởng tượng bạn làm một cái gì đó trong suốt 2 năm trời và sau đó đổ sông đổ bể cả chỉ vì một sai lầm nhỏ vào một ngày nào đó. Bạn nhận ra rằng trong khi đồng đội của bạn vui vẻ và lúc nào cũng có thể cười cợt rằng bạn sẽ không thể chết được, thì sự thật lại ngược lại: bạn học cách trân trọng từng chặng đường đi và hướng đến tương lai trong từng việc bạn làm hàng ngày ngay kể cả những lúc khó khăn nhất. Bạn sẽ nghe người ta nói rằng đừng để quá tụt dốc khi mọi thứ tồi tệ và cũng đừng quá phởn chí khi mọi sự đang tốt, và bạn thậm chí còn đi khuyên người khác những điều tương tự. Nhưng bạn sẽ không bao giờ chấp nhận sự lờ đờ, chẳng bứt lên mà cũng chẳng kém đi vì điều này không thú vị chút nào. Ngay kể cả khi mọi thử đảo lộn hoàn toàn những gì bạn dự định thì cũng là một điều đáng để ăn mừng. Tự nhiên bạn lại cứ thích đâm đầu vào các thử thách khó nhất chỉ vì có một mối liên hệ trực tiếp giữa độ khó của công việc với cảm giác sung sướng khi làm những điều tưởng chừng không thể.</p>

<p>Bạn nhận ra rằng sẽ thú vị hơn nhiều khi bạn không có tiền và tiền đôi khi lại là thứ tồi tệ nhất là khi lấy nó làm mục tiêu cá nhân. Nếu bạn đủ may mắn để cảm thấy như vậy, đó thật sự là một cảm giác gần với sự bình yên vì bạn nhận ra những gì bạn làm là thử thách và cũng là công việc bạn yêu quý. Tài sản của bạn là sự tự do, chủ động, trách nhiệm và sự công nhận. Những thứ này cũng sẽ là những tài sản giá trị mà những người bạn muốn chiến đấu cùng cũng tôn trọng.</p>

<p>Bạn cảm thấy như thể những ông bố bà mẹ với khách hàng và họ sẽ không bao giờ hiểu được bạn yêu họ như thế nào vì chính họ là minh chứng cho việc bạn không điên rồ. Bạn muôn ôm lấy tất cả bọn họ. Và họ có ý nghĩa như là cả thế giới đối với bạn.</p>

<p>Những gì học được phần lớn là từ sự tự trải nghiệm, nhiều hơn bất cứ yếu tố bẩm sinh nào của một Entrepreneur. Bạn nhận ra rằng bạn cần làm gì khi nhận những cú đấm tả tơi vào mặt rất rất nhiều lần. Bạn nhận ra rằng điều bạn cần làm là khi chẳng có ai để ý và chẳng có ai nhìn ra. Bạn nhận ra rằng bạn kém đủ mọi thứ, và thật may mắn nếu bạn giỏi một kỹ năng nào đó. Và thứ duy nhất tuyệt vời có lẽ được là chính mình. Đó cũng là lý do bạn không bao giờ thỏa hiệp. Bạn học được quyền lực và vị thế có thể gây nghiện đến như thế nào và vì sao nó lại có thể tha hóa nhiều người đến vậy.</p>

<p>Bạn sẽ vô cùng biết ơn những quãng thời gian tồi tệ. Trong các ngành nghề khác rất hiếm khi thấy cảnh này. Khi điều tồi tệ xẩy đến, sẽ có những người đến giúp bạn không ngần ngại. Tal Raviv, Gary Smith, Joe Reyes, Toan Dang, Vincent Cheung, Eric Elinow, Abe Marciano và những người khác nữa. Tôi nợ họ cả đời và không gì có thể đền đáp họ được cũng như họ cũng chẳng mong đợi sự đền đáp của tôi.</p>

<p>Bạn bắt đầu nhận ra trong đời, những người may mắn nhất thế giới sẽ chỉ một lần là một phần nào đó của điều gì đó vĩ đại. Biết điều này giúp bạn hợp lý hóa sự toàn tâm của bạn.</p>

<p>Tóm lại, tham gia một công ty startup rất thú vị. Mỗi ngày một khác và đều thú vị cả. Ngay cả khi đó là một ngày tồi tệ cũng vẫn rất thú vị. Biết được rằng các quyết định của bạn không chỉ tác động đến bạn mà còn rất nhiều người khác nữa sẽ là một gánh nặng bạn sẵn sàng chịu đựng hàng ngày còn hơn là không làm chủ được tương lai vận mệnh của mình. Đó là lý do tại sao tôi không thể làm gì khác.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2015-01-22-paul-graham-startup-curve.png"></p>

<h1>Original Post</h1>

<hr />

<p>Very tough to sleep most nights of the week. Weekends don&rsquo;t mean anything to you anymore. Closing a round of financing is not a relief. It means more people are depending on you to turn their investment into 20 times what they gave you.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s very difficult to &ldquo;turn it off&rdquo;. But at the same time, television, movies and vacations become so boring to you when your company&rsquo;s future might be sitting in your inbox or in the results of a new A/B test you decide to run.</p>

<p>You feel guilty when you&rsquo;re doing something you like doing outside of the company. Only through years of wrestling with this internal fight do you recognize how the word &ldquo;balance&rdquo; is an art that is just as important as any other skill set you could ever hope to have. You begin to see how valuable creativity is and that you must think differently not only to win, but to see the biggest opportunity. You recognize you get your best ideas when you&rsquo;re not staring at a screen. You see immediate returns on healthy distractions.</p>

<p>You start to respect the Duck. Paddle like hell under the water and be smooth and calm on top where everyone can see you. You learn the hard way that if you lose your cool you lose.</p>

<p>You always ask yourself if I am changing the World in a good way? Are people&rsquo;s lives better for having known me?</p>

<p>You are creative and when you have an idea it has no filter before it becomes a reality. This feeling is why you can&rsquo;t do anything else.</p>

<p>You start to see that the word &ldquo;entrepreneur&rdquo; is a personality. It&rsquo;s difficult to talk to your friends that are not risking the same things you are because they are content with not pushing themselves or putting it all out there in the public with the likelihood of failure staring at you everyday. You start to turn a lot of your conversations with relatives into how they might exploit opportunities for profit. Those close to you will view your focus as something completely different because they don&rsquo;t understand. You don&rsquo;t blame them. They can&rsquo;t understand if they haven&rsquo;t done it themselves. It&rsquo;s why you will gravitate towards other entrepreneurs. You will find reward in helping other entrepreneurs. This is my email: <a href="&#109;&#97;&#x69;&#108;&#x74;&#111;&#58;&#112;&#97;&#x75;&#x6c;&#x40;&#101;&#99;&#113;&#117;&#105;&#114;&#101;&#46;&#99;&#111;&#109;&#x2e;">&#x70;&#x61;&#117;&#x6c;&#64;&#x65;&#99;&#113;&#x75;&#x69;&#114;&#101;&#x2e;&#99;&#111;&#109;&#46;</a> Let me know if I can help you with anything.</p>

<p>Your job is to create a vision, a culture, to get the right people on the bus and to inspire. When you look around at a team that believes in the vision as much as you do and trusts you will do the right thing all the time, it&rsquo;s a feeling that can&rsquo;t be explained. The exponential productivity from great people will always amaze you. It&rsquo;s why finding the right team is the most difficult thing you will do but the most important. This learning will affect your life significantly. You will not settle for things anymore because you will see what is possible when you hold out for the best and push to find people that are the best. You don&rsquo;t have a problem anymore being honest with people about not cutting it.</p>

<p>You start to see that you&rsquo;re a leader and you have to lead or you can&rsquo;t be involved with it at all. You turn down acquisition offers because you need to run the show and you feel like your team is the best in the World and you can do anything with hard work. Quitting is not an option.</p>

<p>You have to be willing to sleep in your car and laugh about it. You have to be able to laugh at many things because when you think of the worse things in the World that could happen to your company, they will happen. Imagine working for something for two years and then have to throw it out completely because you see in one day that it&rsquo;s wrong. You realize that if your team is having fun and can always laugh that you won&rsquo;t die, and in fact, the opposite will happen: you will learn to love the journey and look forward to what you do everyday even at the lowest times. You&rsquo;ll hear not to get too low when things are bad and not to get too high when things are good and you&rsquo;ll even give that advice. But you&rsquo;ll never take it because being in the middle all the time isn&rsquo;t exciting and an even keel is never worth missing out on something worth celebrating. You&rsquo;ll become addicted to finding the hardest challenges because there&rsquo;s a direct relationship between how difficult something is and the euphoria of a feeling when you do the impossible.</p>

<p>You realize that it&rsquo;s much more fun when you didn&rsquo;t have money and that money might be the worse thing you could have as a personal goal. If you&rsquo;re lucky enough to genuinely feel this way, it is a surreal feeling that is the closest thing to peace because you realize it&rsquo;s the challenges and the work that you love. Your currencies are freedom, autonomy, responsibility and recognition. Those happen to be the same currencies of the people you want around you.</p>

<p>You feel like a parent to your customers in that they will never realize how much you love them and it is they who validate you are not crazy. You want to hug every one of them. They mean the World to you.</p>

<p>You learn the most about yourself more than any other vocation as an entrepreneur. You learn what you do when you get punched in the face many many times. You learn what you do when no one is looking and when no one would find out. You learn that you are bad at many things, lucky if you&rsquo;re good at a handful of things and the only thing you can ever be great at is being yourself which is why you can never compromise it. You learn how power and recognition can be addicting and see how it could corrupt so many.</p>

<p>You become incredibly grateful for the times that things were going as bad as they possibly could. Most people won&rsquo;t get to see this in any other calling. When things are really bad, there are people that come running to help and don&rsquo;t think twice about it. Tal Raviv, Gary Smith, Joe Reyes, Toan Dang, Vincent Cheung, Eric Elinow, Abe Marciano are some of them. I will forever be in their debt and I could never repay them nor would they want or expect to be repaid.</p>

<p>You begin to realize that in life, the luckiest people in the World only get one shot at being a part of something great. Knowing this helps you make sense of your commitment.</p>

<p>Of all the things said though, it&rsquo;s exciting. Every day is different and so exciting. Even when it&rsquo;s bad it&rsquo;s exciting. Knowing that your decisions will not only affect you but many others is a weight that I would rather have any day than the weight of not controlling my future. That&rsquo;s why I could not do anything else.</p>

<h4><strong>Source:</strong> <a href="http://qr.ae/3YjjZ">Quora</a></h4>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
