<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: thought | Han Ngo]]></title>
  <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/blog/categories/thought/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/"/>
  <updated>2020-06-02T02:20:45+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Han Ngo]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[nntruonghan@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Unconventional]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/the-unconventional/"/>
    <updated>2019-07-17T00:11:35+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/the-unconventional</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You might have known that I&rsquo;m building the software organization called The Dwarves in the last four years. The team reached the size of 50 several months ago. The average member age is around 26. They are smart and talented. They are young, well-educated, and hard-working toward success.</p>

<p>With a different expectation in engineering standard, we rarely hire people outside of our circle. We handpick and recruit the individual whom we feel they are the one matching with the engineering-driven culture that we are pursuing. We also decided to hire high potential freshers and train them from scratch. It&rsquo;s costly to do such a thing, but we believe good things take time. That&rsquo;s the way we hire for culture (and values).</p>

<p>The culture we are pursuing is the combination between the unconventional spirit and the will to do the right things in every piece of our decision, not just follow the existing of which has been said for years. From the outside perspective, it seems to be ridiculous to develop such an organization:</p>

<ul>
<li>from gather people with like mind and build the organization we&rsquo;d love to work at</li>
<li>where judgments are fair and run by the right ideas</li>
<li>people payout are equal to their contribution so they can make money and be cool at the same time</li>
<li>people should commit to the quality, not the sales quantity</li>
<li>the team members have time to think about the next problem they want to solve or can join the team on self-development progress.</li>
</ul>


<p>It&rsquo;s like Utopia for software engineers and innovators.</p>

<p>The thought about an unusual business approach, high risk, and considerable chances to fail often appear in my head. But things are getting confident in me over time. There are few companies out there did the same thing, and they stood out.</p>

<p>Remember when Steve Job talked about why he didn&rsquo;t hire the professional managers? In the fast-paced industry like tech, the developer turned manager rule the works. The professional managers can&rsquo;t do crap about that. Managing at Dwarves Foundation is a part-time occupation, next to being involved with doing the work itself.</p>

<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rQKis2Cfpeo" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<p><strong>And running by ideas is the best way to hire great people.</strong></p>

<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/f60dheI4ARg" allowfullscreen></iframe></div></p>

<p><strong>Some companies care about the work output, not chairs.</strong></p>

<p><a href="https://basecamp.com/books/remote"><img src="/images/blog/2019-07-16-guessing.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p><strong>Or when they accept the truth that planning is guessing.</strong></p>

<p><a href="https://basecamp.com/books/rework"><img src="/images/blog/2019-07-16-planning.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>

<p>I love the unconventional way they see and describe the world, not in the fascinating prism but the true nature.</p>

<p>We seek those kinds of people to join our team. The one which is distinctive, with a different approach and can see things in their bare form, know the truth, and be optimistic about the future are the right people we&rsquo;d love to work.</p>

<p>Recently, an intern shared <a href="https://qz.com/1279371/this-physicists-ideas-of-time-will-blow-your-mind/">this post</a> about quantum physics, time and it blew my mind. It reminds me of how lucky I am to have them in the team.</p>

<p>Tech industry is the destination and interference zone between sectors. It&rsquo;s the most fast-pacing environment and the future where human will put all the effort to push its boundary. The Dwarves are running along with the world, and we are welcome you to join us on this journey. We can&rsquo;t promise you the world, but we can guarantee you it will be a fun ride.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Software Engineering Philosophy]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/software-engineering-philosophy/"/>
    <updated>2019-05-23T19:49:02+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/software-engineering-philosophy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/blog/2019-05-23-software.png"></p>

<h1>Software is changing the world</h1>

<p>Software is all around us, yet few people think much about the many ways that software impacts the world every day. The history of computing is often said to start with the tactical problems engineers needed to solve in World War II, but it wasn&rsquo;t until 1941 that engineer Konrad Zuse designed a digital computer capable of using software to solve general problems. During the 1950s, standardized programming languages emerged from the need to reproduce old software on new hardware. By the 1960s, software &ndash; until then given away for free with new computers &ndash; was being produced and sold to end users. By the 1980s, software companies saw the potential in the user-friendly graphical interfaces we are now familiar with. Apple started producing operating systems in the mid-1980s and Microsoft in the early 1990s, leading to the era of convenient and fast software. Internet was invented in 1983 with cloud computing and big data era follow up in the next 20 years. Decentralization with p2p communication, blockchain and bitcoin are booming up in the last 5 years. Today, software is all around us.</p>

<p>Software is used by businesses to communicate worldwide. It is used to operate some of the most complex medical machines. It regulates nuclear plants, electrical grids, and other utilities that provide the basics of life. Of course, it is also behind the safe operation of more than 31 million commercial airline flights in the U.S. each year.</p>

<p>Software also helps make life convenient. For example, computer software has made it easier than ever to connect with friends all over the world using social networks. As software becomes more integrated into electronics and appliances, it will continue to simplify life&rsquo;s challenges. As an example, everyone is familiar with how much easier it is to drive from point A to point B thanks to on-board GPS software. Refrigerators can now notify owners about spoiled food; lights around town and in your home can brighten when they detect you walking in the dark; televisions can make suggestions and record your favorite shows based on your preferences.</p>

<p>Whatever the future holds, it is a good bet that software will remain a very important part of it. As computer software becomes more sophisticated, it will help people with more complex challenges. In the future, software may even help us to regulate and improve our own bodies! Today&rsquo;s wearable technology and implanted medical devices are just the beginning of what the next generation of software can do.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s the pass to future. The performance and survival of a large number of organizations now depend on their ability to integrate digital at the heart of their business strategy. The world can&rsquo;t operate without software.</p>

<h1>The Dwarf Principles</h1>

<p>Our definition of Engineering Philosophy, the guiding ideas that help to shape up the way we think and work, to ensure the core values and to deliver quality softwares.</p>

<p>The performance and survival of a large number of organizations now depend on their ability to integrate digital at the heart of their business strategy. This manifesto documents 15 principles that, our team believes, are the cornerstone to creating exceptional digital products that reach their objectives and stand the test of time.</p>

<h2><strong>Engineering Drive</strong></h2>

<p><em>We build a company where software engineering discipline could shine, innovative and quality products are shipped and change the world for the better.</em></p>

<h4>SYSTEMATIC DISCIPLINE</h4>

<p>Software engineering is an engineering discipline that’s applied to the development of software in a systematic approach.</p>

<p>Not applying software engineering methods results in more expensive, less reliable software, and it can be detrimental on the long term, as the changes come in, the costs will dramatically increase.</p>

<h4>ENGINEERS ARE NOT COMMODITIES</h4>

<p>In every software, the engineering team is one of the most imporant factors to make it successful. Software is more of an artisanship, and software engineers aren&rsquo;t a replaceable cog.</p>

<p>People have an assembly line mindset left over from the industrial age. Don’t believe the one-size-fits-all interview process with whiteboarding problems. These serve to grind away the individuality and make us feel like an assembly line worker.</p>

<h4>THE BEST IDEA WINS</h4>

<p>If you have a great idea and the will to see it through, you can effect great change. Nothing is off limits—we’re constantly looking for improvements in our products, our processes, and our people.</p>

<p>All voices are equal here—we hire people to have an opinion and be creative. If your idea makes the most sense, that’s what we’re doing, regardless of your role or seniority.</p>

<p>We learned the practice from an A team, and it is beneficial by helping to strengthen the flat organizational structure.</p>

<p><img class="left half" src="/images/blog/2019-05-23-dwarf.png"></p>

<h2><strong>The Craftsmanship</strong></h2>

<h4>WELL-CRAFTED SOFTWARE</h4>

<p>We humbly demonstrate our expertise by delivering quality software. We work toward perfection in every single piece that we produce. We are proud of the well-crafted software that we develop together. We do not tolerate preventable defects.</p>

<h4>QUALITY PAYS</h4>

<p>Good things take time. Quality must be the top priority. In software work, quality problems overwhelm everything else. When quality isn&rsquo;t managed, entire software projects are unmanageable. Software development is intellectual work. Crafting a high quality software requires not just lots of efforts from a team but also the disciplines and proper methods.</p>

<h4>MIND THE DETAILS</h4>

<p>Details matter. We believe small details equate to big success. As such, creating a product that charms users involves adjusting, refining, and perfecting, over and over again. This attention to detail makes all the difference and creates memorable user experiences.</p>

<h4>CHOOSING THE BORING SOLUTION</h4>

<p>Software development is complex enough by nature. When in doubt, go with the boring solution. Using such a boring solution means that you&rsquo;re using simple vocabulary, which greatly increases the chances of everybody understanding you. This will make it a lot easier for everybody to follow along.</p>

<h4>THINK LONG-TERM</h4>

<p>We do not believe in rushing for project and working overtime. We believe in working sustainably and balanced so that we are a happy bunch of sane workers. Software requires good brains to create good codes and good processes. We do not burn out.</p>

<h4>APPLICATIONS NEED SOLID FOUNDATIONS</h4>

<p>Quality products always rely on a solid foundation. There will be a lot of works running on days, weeks, months, and maybe even years building that application. This constant, never-ending maintenance and extension of an application means that its foundation becomes crucial. Much like with a house, it&rsquo;s not a clever idea to save some money by building just a cheap foundation.</p>

<h4>NOTHING IS PERMANENT</h4>

<p>Software moves fast. New technology has enabled us to create new things. The technology you used yesterday maybe deprecated today. Make sure you understand both the old technology and the new one before buying into the next new thing. New technology needs to provide actual value over existing solutions.</p>

<h2><strong>Minifesto</strong></h2>

<h4>RUNNING LEAN</h4>

<p>Lean philosophy regards everything not adding value to the customer as waste. In order to eliminate waste, one should be able to recognize it. Partially done work, extra processes like paperwork and features not often used by customers are waste. Rework or unnecessarily complex solutions are waste. Waiting for other activities, teams, processes is waste. Managerial overhead not producing real value is waste.</p>

<h4>DELIVER AS FAST AS POSSIBLE</h4>

<p>Make it work. Perfect is an enemy of good. Look for perfection, but not yet. First do it, then do it right, then do it better. Any sufficiently complex system cannot be built out of design, it has to be evolved. The shorter the iterations, the better the learning and communication within the team. The sooner the end product is delivered without major defects, the sooner feedback can be received, and incorporated into the next iteration.</p>

<h4>AIM FOR SIMPLICITY</h4>

<p>Simplicity is complicated. Simple is harder than complex. We have to write code for humans not machines. We want readability. Readable means Reliable. It&rsquo;s easier to understand. It&rsquo;s easier to work on. If it breaks, it&rsquo;s easier to fix.</p>

<h4>EFFECTIVE > PRODUCTIVE</h4>

<p>Being productive is about occupying your time—filling your schedule to the brim and getting as much done as you can. Being effective is about finding more of your time unoccupied and open for other things besides work. We don’t believe in busyness. We believe in effectiveness. Know your priority and do things that matter.</p>

<h4>FAIL FAST, LEARN OFTEN</h4>

<p>Don&rsquo;t be afraid of starting all over again. Evaluate your work constantly. Don&rsquo;t be afraid of throwing to the rubbish a project you&rsquo;ve working on last months. When you start from scratch, innovation comes organically inspired by previous experiences. Evaluate your work constantly.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2019-05-23-team-images.png"></p>

<h5>WE ARE HIRING</h5>

<p>We are looking for more Dwarves joining us. Have the same DNA and want to build world class products with superb team? Find yourself a seat at: <a href="https://dwarves.careers">https://dwarves.careers</a></p>

<p>We build a dynamic environment where engineers can spend their time working with disruptive startups and be cool at the same time. Checkout engineering life at Dwarves Foundation: <a href="https://dwarves.careers/life/">https://dwarves.careers/life/</a></p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2019-05-23-engineering-life.png"></p>

<blockquote><p>Here&rsquo;s our cat</p></blockquote>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2019-05-23-cat.JPG"></p>

<p>&mdash;</p>

<p>The web version: <a href="https://d.foundation/manifesto">https://d.foundation/manifesto</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2018: Year of Achievement]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/2018-year-of-achievement/"/>
    <updated>2019-01-26T14:41:20+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/2018-year-of-achievement</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/blog/2019-01-26-homepage.png"></p>

<p>Dwarves Foundation is a software development firm that based in South East Asia. Starting in 2014, we use cutting-edge technology to help tech startups, entrepreneurs and makers to deliver world-class software products.</p>

<h1>The Dwarves of the Year</h1>

<p>Many endeavors have significantly been made by our Dwarves to keep our boat moving over the past year. We have seen the sweat they drop. We have seen the effort they give. We have seen the time we spent together and we cannot stop ourselves treasuring those moments. It gratifies the team to eventually hold an award for the Dwarves of the year.</p>

<p>We understand that success does not come by accident. Breakthrough arrives after hours of working and trying. It pushes us through many considerations to finally reach to these three top-notch nominees among those remarkable hard works:</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2019-01-26-hall-of-fame.png"></p>

<h3>Huy Nguyen — Outstanding</h3>

<p>Considered for his dynamic contribution, Huy distinguishes himself for being enthusiasm towards the work. His striking performance was shown throughout multiple products. Appears to be the frequent workaholic who dedicates his time more than others, Huy did achieve a remarkable growth.
Beside successfully improving the internal competency, Huy is highly recognized for being a dedicated trainer for interns and co-workers.</p>

<h3>Thanh Pham — Honorable Mention</h3>

<p>Thanh differentiates his work performance during the process of development which assigned him the superior skills on visual and animation. Apart from being a devoted employee, he also plays an integral part of backing up the team and training front-end juniors.
Nevertheless, Thanh finds himself hard to fit in with other Dwarves, which explains the reason his ability in leadership is still in need of improvement.</p>

<h3>Hieu Nguyen — Honorable Mention</h3>

<p>Along with achieving breakthrough change on technical skills and meeting deadline on time with high standard workability, Hieu is well known for being proactive and eager to learn new things. Hieu also proves himself as an adept for new Dwarves to look up and get feedback from.
Though he truly give his best for the work, Hieu’s limited ability of teamwork and leadership still prevents him from being more outstanding.</p>

<p>As there is nothing that can help us measure the contribution you have put, we decided to conduct the award by different means. They are expected to claim the prize based on their titles both in cash and in kind, along with a certificate of recognition as a proof of accomplishment, as well as being honored on our Hall of Fame. Every single piece of trying helps us gradually expand the picture. Live long and prosper has been chosen as one of the mindsets to constitute our woodland from the very first day.</p>

<p>For the sake of that to happen, we understand that their benefit comes parallel to the team. So it will be dead wrong if you think there is a benchmark for the means of award. At Dwarves Foundation, recognition does not work that way. The more they contribute, the more guerdon they receive.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2019-01-26-certificate.jpg"></p>

<h1>2018</h1>

<p>2018 has been a fulfilling year for us with many achievements.</p>

<p>We adapted the new team structure; we redefined things we value.</p>

<p>We doubled the office space. We welcomed new dwarves to join us.</p>

<p>We scaled up from 15 to 40ish with all the smart people gathering around and commit to the dream of building our first global software firm.</p>

<p>We learn new ways to get things done; we live by that for a cutting edge product quality. And we wrap it up with the tedious belief of a better triumph.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2019-01-26-year-end-party.jpeg"></p>

<p>Everything is just the beginning of our first chapters and it couldn’t be that great without you. I’m very thankful for all the contributions that you have made and looking forward to 2019 with all of you.</p>

<hr />

<h3>We are hiring</h3>

<p>As we are expanding in 2019, we are looking for more Dwarves joining us. Find yourself a seat at: <a href="https://dwarves.careers">https://dwarves.careers</a></p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2019-01-26-tech-stack.png"></p>

<p>Read more at: <a href="http://bit.ly/dwarves-foundation-2018">Medium</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Dwarves Foundation Stand For]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/what-dwarves-foundation-stand-for/"/>
    <updated>2018-03-19T10:30:20+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/what-dwarves-foundation-stand-for</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Innovation happens. There are many startups found and raise fund every day. They focus on making significant positive changes, impact millions of people, lead to breakthroughs and support the foundation of economic growth.</p>

<p>Building an innovation startup requires lots of different things, and it is tough. Most of them have to deal with business development, legal, fundraising, team recruitment, and product development at the same time. Tech startups need to move fast and break things.</p>

<p>At some points, growing a startup needs a strong and experienced team behind. The software team that can help to design the system, design the database, produce the well-crafted software, keep the system stable, avoid the technical debt and deliver values is one of the critical pieces to solve the puzzle.</p>

<p>Another motivations for Dwarves Foundation was the lack of respect that service firms receive. Most software companies out there focus on digital transformation and consultancy. They do tricks. They hit and run. The codebase they produced is full of crap and it damages our pride.</p>

<p>This is where Dwarves Foundation comes in.
Despite the fact that service firms scale linearly, their ultimate size is capped and small, they don’t have life-changing exits for their founders, we start Dwarves Foundation as we want to build things right. I’ve always felt that companies like Dwarves Foundation are more important to the economy than the mildly pejorative phrase used to describe them.</p>

<p>Dwarves Foundation is an innovation service firm. We have been building an organization with high standard software practices and business growth capabilities, helping tech startups, entrepreneurs and makers deliver their innovative software product since 2013.</p>

<p><strong>We stand for the craftsmanship in software development</strong>. More than telling people how to do things, as a firm, we take responsibility for collaboratively creating the product of innovation with the client. We value the long-term partnership, and we brought the economic impact through massive product distribution and brought to the market by the clients.</p>

<p>We empower innovation with software craftsmanship. This is what we do here. It takes many forms, and we’re always working towards it.</p>

<h3>The Dwarves</h3>

<p>The story begins in Norse Mythology. After the executed of Ymir, the very first giant of the universe, by Odin has conceived a whole new universe. In the new world, Yggdrasill is a giant ash tree located at the center cradles the nine realms of the cosmos.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2018-03-19-yggdrasill.png"></p>

<p>Dwarf is the small and misshapen creatures that originated as maggots from Ymir’s corpse. They dwell in the mountains deep down in the dark underground of <strong>Svartalfheim</strong>. Dwarves are wisdom, natural good at smithing, mining, and crafting. They are well known for being the best blacksmiths throughout the nine worlds, not only do they have natural abilities to craft weapons and jewelry. They are also excellent engineers and architects.</p>

<p>Dwarvish magic was fundamentally technological know how. They had an unusually high level of skill. There was no shimmering light around the Dwarves, just first rate workmanship. Dwarves greatly pride themselves in their craftsmanship, be it smithing or anything else.</p>

<p>The dwarf is an example of a creature who has the ability that surpasses the known world, presaging the rise of a universe beyond this physical realm. Whatever their origin, the dwarf’s existence plays a role in expanding the imagination.</p>

<p>Aspiring to create a positive breakthrough that can be able to rewrite the new world, we chose the name Dwarves Foundation as the commitment to the vision that we follow.</p>

<p>At our woodland, the Dwarves are encouraged to thoroughly assess and evaluate the product quality before handing it to the customers. By participate in every detail of the work, we take craftsmanship as one of the most fundamental factors of the career transformation for engineers. World-class products require world-class engineers and craftsmanship is what makes it done. Craftsmanship is what flows among the team spirit, or does not exist at all.</p>

<p>We choose innovation to be one of our core values that form ideas to affect the general society undoubtedly. Innovation is not for geniuses working alone, it is an activity that requires the team effort. Being innovative is a part to approach the new era. What that rewards, what can I say, can genuinely lead to significantly remodel the cosmo.</p>

<p><img src="/images/blog/2018-03-19-dwarves.jpg"></p>

<hr />

<p>Empower innovation is the lifestyle we choose and we are always welcome the like minded people to join us on this journey. A network with all the people who want to change the world would be really awesome. Drop us a message <a href="&#109;&#x61;&#x69;&#x6c;&#x74;&#111;&#58;&#116;&#x65;&#x61;&#x6d;&#x40;&#x64;&#46;&#x66;&#x6f;&#x75;&#x6e;&#x64;&#97;&#116;&#105;&#x6f;&#110;">&#116;&#101;&#97;&#x6d;&#x40;&#x64;&#46;&#x66;&#111;&#x75;&#110;&#x64;&#97;&#x74;&#x69;&#x6f;&#110;</a> anytime.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go and Elixir]]></title>
    <link href="http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/go-and-elixir/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-11T14:24:20+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://tieubao.github.io/writing/a/go-and-elixir</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m the founder of Dwarves Foundation, a software development firm that based in South East Asia. We use both languages in production and have developed some web apps, systems using Go and Elixir.</p>

<p>First of all, I have to say both languages are great, same as the communities. They are both concurrency languages, but there are some differences in their souls.</p>

<p>If you come from the background of Python, Go take the same approach of &lsquo;manual language.&rsquo; Go is a minimal language. Go replaces the inheritance by the composition (which said by someone &ldquo;Inheritance was a bad dream that (most) people have woken up from.&rdquo;) There is no magic in Go source code. Also, with the support of &lsquo;gofmt&rsquo; (syntax formatter), it brings you the transparency of knowledge between your source code and others. You will feel no hesitation to read the source code of your friends or open source libraries in Github.</p>

<p><strong>Go is the best fit for API services and command line tool development</strong>. Go is a &lsquo;have-to-learn&rsquo; language for engineers.</p>

<p>Go brings you the feel of &lsquo;it just works&rsquo; language after years working with it in several projects. Talking a little bit more about Go web frameworks, they do have a good framework for web development: Gin, echo, goji &hellip; are the minimal one like Flask, Express or Sinatra; Beego, Revel are full-fledged or battery included frameworks like Django, Sails or Rails. However, at the end of the day, you don&rsquo;t want to use those frameworks or ORMs at all, you will just want to use built-in components of Go to build your new system. That&rsquo;s the moment when you have been enlightened to feel the minimalism of Go. &ldquo;It just works,&rdquo; the gopher in you will speak to yourself.</p>

<p>You can take reference to <a href="https://github.com/mattermost/mattermost-server">mattermost</a> repository to learn more the stack of Go as API server and React for web front-end.</p>

<hr />

<p>After the long time working with Go and if you are the type of lazy developers, you will find that Go language itself isn&rsquo;t wise enough. Go makes sense outside of the web dev world. As a web developer, you still need the super fast speed, but you want something as cool as Rails, Elixir/Phoenix is good for you.</p>

<ul>
<li>Functional Programming vs. OOP (<a href="https://medium.com/@brianwill/object-oriented-programming-a-personal-disaster-1b044c2383ab">Object-Oriented Programming: A Disaster Story</a>)</li>
<li>Fault tolerance. It&rsquo;s something Go doesn&rsquo;t have. If an Erlang process (not an OS process, an Erlang process) dies, it dies. Every other process on the system is fine and Erlang has facilities to have processes monitor other processes and bring each other back up if one dies. It&rsquo;s just amazing. Absolutely beautiful.</li>
<li>Abstract Syntax Trees. The one that brings <strong>Homoiconicity</strong> which is believed to be the source of power of Lisp.</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<p>We are soldiers. We use different guns or knives in different purposes.
At the moment, our stack is as below.</p>

<ul>
<li>Go for API server, cmd line tools, and DevOps scripts.</li>
<li>Elixir for web development.</li>
<li>Vue.js for frontend development</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
